<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ResearchBuzz - Transformed</title>
    <link>https://researchbuzz.me</link>
    <description>News and resources covering social media, search engines, databases, archives, and other such information collections. Since 1998.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 06:39:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Government unveils a new era of community driven tourism innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.standardmedia.co.ke/national/article/2001535991/government-unveils-a-new-era-of-community-driven-tourism-innovation</link>
      <description>The Standard (Kenya): &amp;#8220;As part of this transformative agenda, the Cabinet Secretary noted that the Kenyatta International Convention Centre (KICC) has unveiled a Virtual Exhibition Platform, a pioneering digital marketplace that will showcase Kenyan cultural artists, products, services, and destinations to both local and global audiences.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.standardmedia.co.ke/national/article/2001535991/government-unveils-a-new-era-of-community-driven-tourism-innovation</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At AI’s biggest gathering, its inner workings remain a mystery</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/ai-progress-surges-researchers-struggle-explain-rcna247693</link>
      <description>NBC News: &amp;#8220;For the past week, academics, startup founders and researchers representing industrial titans from around the globe descended on sunny San Diego for the top gathering in the field of artificial intelligence. The Neural Information Processing Systems, or NeurIPS, conference has been held for 39 years, but it drew a record-breaking 26,000 attendees this year, twice as many as just six years ago.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/ai-progress-surges-researchers-struggle-explain-rcna247693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X shuts down the European Commission’s ad account the day after major fine</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/social-media/x-shuts-down-the-european-commissions-ad-account-the-day-after-major-fine-173553267.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;Just a day after receiving a roughly $140 million fine, X has terminated the ad account of the European Commission. Nikita Bier, X&amp;#8217;s head of product, accused the European Commission of using an exploit to artificially boost the reach of its post announcing the major fine.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/social-media/x-shuts-down-the-european-commissions-ad-account-the-day-after-major-fine-173553267.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia Has Its Own Version of ‘Wrapped’ Now, But There’s One Little Problem</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/wikipedia-has-its-own-version-of-wrapped-now-but-theres-one-little-problem-2000696361</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;If you happen to use the Wikipedia app, you can open it now and see stats like how many minutes you spent reading on the app, how many articles you visited, and which topics you were most interested in this year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/wikipedia-has-its-own-version-of-wrapped-now-but-theres-one-little-problem-2000696361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navy stands up its first information warfare squadron</title>
      <link>https://taskandpurpose.com/news/navy-information-warfare-squadron/?utm_social_handle_id=9344070&amp;#038;utm_social_post_id=617715721</link>
      <description>Task and Purpose: &amp;#8220;The Navy is the latest service to get into the information warfare fight. On Friday, Naval Information Forces stood up the Information Warfare Squadron Two, the first of a new kind of naval intelligence unit meant to support carrier strike groups.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://taskandpurpose.com/news/navy-information-warfare-squadron/?utm_social_handle_id=9344070&amp;#038;utm_social_post_id=617715721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guild of Photojournalists Nigeria, DTML ink partnership to digitally transform Nigeria’s visual heritage</title>
      <link>https://technologytimes.ng/guild-of-photojournalists-nigeria-ink-agreement/</link>
      <description>Technology Times (Nigeria): &amp;#8220;Nigeria’s historic visual record is set for a major digital transformation as Digital Transformation Media Limited (DTML) and the Guild of Photojournalists Nigeria (GPN) have entered into a landmark partnership to preserve, digitise, and monetise decades of photographic work produced by Nigerian photojournalists.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://technologytimes.ng/guild-of-photojournalists-nigeria-ink-agreement/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACLU Sues San Francisco Landlords over AI-Powered Surveillance in Tenants&amp;#8217; Homes</title>
      <link>https://www.aclunc.org/news/aclu-sues-san-francisco-landlords-over-ai-powered-surveillance-tenants-homes</link>
      <description>ACLU Northern California: &amp;#8220;Landlords may say &amp;#8216;smart home&amp;#8217; devices are a tenant convenience. But the reality is, these AI-enabled systems can track patterns of tenant behavior, identify when people are home, and provide landlords with personal information that could be used to push out tenants perceived as too costly.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.aclunc.org/news/aclu-sues-san-francisco-landlords-over-ai-powered-surveillance-tenants-homes</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered police body cameras, once taboo, get tested on Canadian city’s ‘watch list’ of faces</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/ai-facial-recognition-axon-edmonton-21f319ce806a0023f855eb69d928d31e</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;Police body cameras equipped with artificial intelligence have been trained to detect the faces of about 7,000 people on a &amp;#8216;high risk&amp;#8217; watch list in the Canadian city of Edmonton, a live test of whether facial recognition technology shunned as too intrusive could have a place in policing throughout North America.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/ai-facial-recognition-axon-edmonton-21f319ce806a0023f855eb69d928d31e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potentially life-threatening medicine interactions combated with new database</title>
      <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-potentially-life-threatening-medicine-interactions.html</link>
      <description>Medical Xpress: &amp;#8220;A comprehensive webpage-based database, named as IMgateway, currently offers rigorous, evidence-based information on the integration of complementary and conventional medicine but has lacked data on Chinese herbal medicines—until now. A research team, led by Dr. Phoebe Zhou at the National Institute of Complementary Medicines, has added new data to fill this gap, detailing 540 general Chinese herb–drug interactions and 607 individual reports.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-potentially-life-threatening-medicine-interactions.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Slop Is Spurring Record Requests for Imaginary Journals</title>
      <link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/ai-slop-is-spurring-record-requests-for-imaginary-journals/</link>
      <description>Scientific American: &amp;#8220;OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google’s Gemini, Microsoft’s Copilot and other models are befuddling students, researchers and archivists by generating &amp;#8216;incorrect or fabricated archival references,&amp;#8217; according to the ICRC [International Committee of the Red Cross], which runs some of the world’s most used research archives. (Scientific American has asked the owners of those AI models to comment.)&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/ai-slop-is-spurring-record-requests-for-imaginary-journals/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I need more tea. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explore Your Archive: Newly Catalogued Archives</title>
      <link>https://www.library.wales/news/article/explore-your-archive-your-archive</link>
      <description>National Library of Wales: &amp;#8220;As well as the expertise of our staff, who have been exploring a variety of new cataloguing methodologies, we greatly appreciate the help of donors, owners, researchers, volunteers, students and external funding in enabling us to access, understand, arrange, describe and share archives. Here are some of the catalogues that we have completed during 2025; we intend to publish an update in the New Year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.library.wales/news/article/explore-your-archive-your-archive</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding freedom: Trail Finder expands access to the outdoors</title>
      <link>https://vtdigger.org/2025/12/08/finding-freedom-trail-finder-expands-access-to-the-outdoors/</link>
      <description>New-to-me, from VT Digger: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;the Trail Finder team has been able to improve the descriptions and maps for over 125 miles of accessible pedestrian trails on the site. Routes of all types are continuously added, from rail trails to adaptive mountain biking. Website users can click the &amp;#8216;Access(ible) Experience&amp;#8217; search filter to find trails that offer greater levels of access.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vtdigger.org/2025/12/08/finding-freedom-trail-finder-expands-access-to-the-outdoors/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curating in the crossfire: collecting in the time of war and crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.bl.uk/stories/blogs/posts/curating-in-the-crossfire-collecting-in-the-time-of-war-conflict-and-crisis</link>
      <description>British Library: &amp;#8220;From Cold War exchanges to documenting modern conflicts in Ukraine and Gaza, our recent conference examined historical and contemporary initiatives aimed at preserving diverse materials and heritage sites at risk of loss or destruction.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bl.uk/stories/blogs/posts/curating-in-the-crossfire-collecting-in-the-time-of-war-conflict-and-crisis</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discord Checkpoint is the end-of-year recap you never knew you needed</title>
      <link>https://www.howtogeek.com/discord-checkpoint-is-the-end-of-year-recap-you-never-knew-you-needed/</link>
      <description>How-To Geek: &amp;#8220;Discord has finally introduced its own version of the popular annual recap feature with the rollout of Discord Checkpoint for 2025 activity. This is the first time the platform has given users a comprehensive, personalized look back at their yearly habits, and the results are interesting.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.howtogeek.com/discord-checkpoint-is-the-end-of-year-recap-you-never-knew-you-needed/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia continues tech crackdown by blocking Snapchat, FaceTime access</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/12/5/russia-continues-tech-crackdown-by-blocking-snapchat-facetime-access</link>
      <description>Al Jazeera: &amp;#8220;Russian authorities have blocked access to Snapchat and Apple’s video calling service FaceTime in the latest move by Moscow clamping down on foreign tech platforms as it tightens control over the country’s internet and online communications.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/12/5/russia-continues-tech-crackdown-by-blocking-snapchat-facetime-access</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet forgets, but I don’t want to</title>
      <link>https://alexwlchan.net/2025/social-media-scrapbook/</link>
      <description>Alex Chan: &amp;#8220;I want to remember social media, and not just as a vague memory. I want to remember exactly what I read, what I saw, what I wrote. If I was born 50 years ago, I’m the sort of person who’d keep a scrapbook full of letters and postcards – physical traces of the people who mattered to me. Today, those traces are digital. I don’t trust the Internet to remember for me, so I’ve built my own scrapbook of social media. It’s a place where I can save the posts that shaped me, delighted me, or just stuck in my mind.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexwlchan.net/2025/social-media-scrapbook/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This self-hosted Linux app cut my subscription costs by $300</title>
      <link>https://www.howtogeek.com/selfhosted-linux-app-cut-subscription-costs/</link>
      <description>How-To Geek: &amp;#8220;Subscriptions are the new cable, and if you&amp;#8217;re not careful, you might find that your subscription costs wind up creeping higher than any cable subscription ever did. This open-source app is how I keep track of my subscriptions, and how I ultimately saved myself several hundred dollars per year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.howtogeek.com/selfhosted-linux-app-cut-subscription-costs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water leak at Paris Louvre Museum damages books at Egyptian antiquities department</title>
      <link>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/water-leak-paris-louvre-museum-155655418.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;A water leak last month damaged hundreds of books in the Egyptian ​antiquities department at the Louvre, underscoring the deteriorating ‌state of the world&amp;#8217;s most visited museum just weeks after a daring ‌jewel heist exposed security flaws.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/water-leak-paris-louvre-museum-155655418.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do Gen Z have a growing appetite for retro tech?</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckgl8nj8nvzo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</link>
      <description>BBC: &amp;#8220;Gen Z are going retro. People in their teens and early 20s are increasingly turning to old school tech in a bid to unplug from the online world. Amazon UK told BBC Scotland News that retro-themed products surged in popularity during its Black Friday event, with portable vinyl turntables, Tamagotchis and disposable cameras among their best sellers.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckgl8nj8nvzo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorities monitor online criticism of New Orleans immigration crackdown</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/dec/08/new-orleans-immigration-online-criticism-tracking</link>
      <description>The Guardian: &amp;#8220;State and federal authorities are closely tracking online criticism and protests against the Trump administration’s immigration crackdown in New Orleans, monitoring message boards around the clock for threats to agents while compiling regular updates on public “sentiment” surrounding the arrests, according to law enforcement records reviewed by the Associated Press.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/dec/08/new-orleans-immigration-online-criticism-tracking</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drones to Diplomas: How Russia’s Largest Private University is Linked to a $25M Essay Mill</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/12/drones-to-diplomas-how-russias-largest-private-university-is-linked-to-a-25m-essay-mill/</link>
      <description>Krebs on Security: &amp;#8220;A sprawling academic cheating network turbocharged by Google Ads that has generated nearly $25 million in revenue has curious ties to a Kremlin-connected oligarch whose Russian university builds drones for Russia’s war against Ukraine.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/12/drones-to-diplomas-how-russias-largest-private-university-is-linked-to-a-25m-essay-mill/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Listens For Mood Swings In The Voices Of Those With Bipolar Disorder</title>
      <link>https://maniainsights.com/2025/12/06/ai-listens-for-mood-swings-in-the-voices-of-those-with-bipolar-disorder/</link>
      <description>Mania Insights: &amp;#8220;A new study from China suggests that artificial intelligence may one day help doctors spot mood swings in people with bipolar disorder just by listening to how they talk. The experimental system correctly identified manic, depressed, and stable states in Mandarin-speaking patients with around 86% accuracy.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maniainsights.com/2025/12/06/ai-listens-for-mood-swings-in-the-voices-of-those-with-bipolar-disorder/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. The weirdest thing I&amp;#8217;ve found so far while packing is a Duke&amp;#8217;s Mayonnaise thimble (?) Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online database for Arkansas agency rules launches quietly after 5 years, $2.7 million</title>
      <link>https://www.arkansasonline.com/news/2025/dec/07/online-database-for-arkansas-agency-rules/</link>
      <description>Arkansas Democrat-Gazette: &amp;#8220;Without any fanfare, an Arkansas legislative agency launched an online database of the administrative rules of state agencies earlier this year in a project that took more than five years of work to implement at an estimated price tag of $2.7 million.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.arkansasonline.com/news/2025/dec/07/online-database-for-arkansas-agency-rules/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Sheets joins the company&amp;#8217;s productivity suite</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/apps/proton-sheets-joins-the-companys-productivity-suite-110000344.html</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;The latest addition to Proton&amp;#8217;s workplace suite is a spreadsheet tool called Proton Sheets. It will offer real-time collaboration, and users can control who has access to view and edit files. Proton Sheets can also be accessed on any device, including mobile ones. It supports importing CSV and XLS files, and the spreadsheets also support commonly used formulas for calculations.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/apps/proton-sheets-joins-the-companys-productivity-suite-110000344.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prime Video pulls eerily emotionless AI-generated anime dubs after complaints</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/prime-video-pulls-eerily-emotionless-ai-generated-anime-dubs-after-complaints/</link>
      <description>Ars Technica: &amp;#8220;In videos shared by users, some of the AI-generated voice work was eerily deadpan. In one telling video Ash Lynx from Banana Fish tries to awaken a child who has been shot while speaking in a detached, dry tone. &amp;#8216;Don’t leave me please,”&amp;#8217; he states like a robot before confronting someone without any anger in his voice. The person responds in a similarly emotionless manner.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/prime-video-pulls-eerily-emotionless-ai-generated-anime-dubs-after-complaints/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musk, Bezos, and Zuckerberg Are Full of Shit (Literally) in New Art Exhibit</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/musk-bezos-and-zuckerberg-are-full-of-shit-literally-in-new-art-exhibit-2000695745</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;The latest work of the artist Beeple, best known for selling a piece of NFT artwork to some poor schmuck for $69 million at the height of that craze, has attached the heads of the billionaires and some other notable figures to the bodies of robot dogs who aimlessly walk around and take pictures that are pooped out of their machine back ends. It is a comment on…something, for sure.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/musk-bezos-and-zuckerberg-are-full-of-shit-literally-in-new-art-exhibit-2000695745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Museum activities in Uzbekistan will be digitized and developed</title>
      <link>https://one.uz/en/news/uzbekistan/27878-museum-activities-in-uzbekistan-will-be-digitized-and-developed.html</link>
      <description>ONE (Uzbekistan): &amp;#8220;In this regard, an important draft decision aimed at developing museum services and increasing tourist flow through the introduction of modern technologies is being prepared. The document is expected to be approved by the Cabinet of Ministers. This decision aims to expand services in museums, create comfortable conditions for visitors, and introduce digital technologies.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://one.uz/en/news/uzbekistan/27878-museum-activities-in-uzbekistan-will-be-digitized-and-developed.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMS Phishers Pivot to Points, Taxes, Fake Retailers</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/12/sms-phishers-pivot-to-points-taxes-fake-retailers/</link>
      <description>Krebs On Security: &amp;#8220;Over the past week, thousands of domain names were registered for scam websites that purport to offer T-Mobile customers the opportunity to claim a large number of rewards points. The phishing domains are being promoted by scam messages sent via Apple’s iMessage service or the functionally equivalent RCS messaging service built into Google phones.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/12/sms-phishers-pivot-to-points-taxes-fake-retailers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitch star QTCinderella says she wishes she never started streaming</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3v1dd01x65o?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</link>
      <description>BBC: &amp;#8220;Throughout 2025, several female content creators have spoken out about concerns of their safety, particularly when attending public events. In March, three US Twitch streamers, Cinna, Valkyrae and Emiru, were taking part in a week-long marathon stream when a man threatened to kill them. Then, at the annual streamer event TwitchCon in October, a man from the crowd grabbed Emiru and tried to kiss her without her consent.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3v1dd01x65o?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People negatively judge others who glitch on video calls, according to study</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/video-call-internet-gitches-effect-on-your-brain</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;According to a new study published this week in Nature, audiovisual glitches can have far-reaching affects on users that extend beyond expected nuisances, but which have the power to fundamentally impact major areas of our life, including the outcome of a job interview, trust in medical professionals, and the result of legal proceedings. And for people who don&amp;#8217;t have reliable internet access, including digitally disconnected, rural, or low-income households, the impact may be even more severe.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/video-call-internet-gitches-effect-on-your-brain</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonmedical TikTok creators outperform doctors in engagement on SSRI videos</title>
      <link>https://www.psypost.org/nonmedical-tiktok-creators-outperform-doctors-in-engagement-on-ssri-videos/</link>
      <description>PsyPost: &amp;#8220;An analysis of TikTok videos on SSRIs showed that medical professionals generally maintained a neutral tone in those videos, while nonmedical professionals were more likely to adopt a positive tone. Videos by nonmedical professionals tended to have more views, likes, and comments.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.psypost.org/nonmedical-tiktok-creators-outperform-doctors-in-engagement-on-ssri-videos/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. The weirdest thing I&amp;#8217;ve found so far while packing is a Duke&amp;#8217;s Mayonnaise thimble (?) Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voices of Mount Zion Hospital: Physician Oral Histories Digitized and Online</title>
      <link>https://www.library.ucsf.edu/news/mount-zion-oral-histories-1995-1997/</link>
      <description>UC San Francisco: &amp;#8220;A trove of 54 oral-history audio recordings from Mount Zion Hospital, now part of the University of California, San Francisco (UCSF) Medical Center at Mount Zion, conducted between 1995 and 1997, is now available online.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.library.ucsf.edu/news/mount-zion-oral-histories-1995-1997/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massachusetts court hears arguments in lawsuit alleging Meta designed apps to be addictive to kids</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/facebook-instagram-lawsuit-massachusetts-d5d12197563a92796821b56a20b7d89b</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;Massachusetts’ highest court heard oral arguments Friday in the state’s lawsuit arguing that Meta designed features on Facebook and Instagram to make them addictive to young users.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/facebook-instagram-lawsuit-massachusetts-d5d12197563a92796821b56a20b7d89b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft drops AI sales targets in half after salespeople miss their quotas</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/12/microsoft-slashes-ai-sales-growth-targets-as-customers-resist-unproven-agents/</link>
      <description>Ars Technica: &amp;#8220;Microsoft has lowered sales growth targets for its AI agent products after many salespeople missed their quotas in the fiscal year ending in June, according to a report Wednesday from The Information. The adjustment is reportedly unusual for Microsoft, and it comes after the company missed a number of ambitious sales goals for its AI offerings.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/12/microsoft-slashes-ai-sales-growth-targets-as-customers-resist-unproven-agents/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looks Like We Can Finally Kiss the Metaverse Goodbye</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/looks-like-we-can-finally-kiss-the-metaverse-goodbye-2000695825</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;According to a report from Bloomberg, Meta is expected to slash its Reality Labs budget, shaving off as much as 30%. Those cuts may be imminent, too, arriving as soon as January as Meta prepares its budget for the new calendar year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/looks-like-we-can-finally-kiss-the-metaverse-goodbye-2000695825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help us save the digital archives of local newsrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.poynter.org/reporting-editing/2025/help-us-save-the-digital-archives-of-local-newsrooms/</link>
      <description>Poynter: &amp;#8220;Earlier this year, we announced a new program Poynter is part of called Today’s News for Tomorrow. This Press Forward-funded project from the Internet Archive, IRE and Poynter will work with 300 local newsrooms of all shapes, sizes and mediums over the next two years to make sure those drafts get preserved and people have access to them. We’ll host three groups a year, with three live virtual sessions and three asynchronous sessions for the newsrooms chosen to take part.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.poynter.org/reporting-editing/2025/help-us-save-the-digital-archives-of-local-newsrooms/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia blocks Roblox, citing &amp;#8216;LGBT propaganda&amp;#8217; as a reason</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/gaming/russia-blocks-roblox-citing-lgbt-propaganda-as-a-reason-180757267.html?guccounter=1</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;Russia has blocked the popular gaming platform Roblox, according to a report by Reuters. The country&amp;#8217;s communications watchdog Roskomnadzor accused the developers of distributing extremist materials and &amp;#8216;LGBT propaganda.&apos;&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/gaming/russia-blocks-roblox-citing-lgbt-propaganda-as-a-reason-180757267.html?guccounter=1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk’s Grok AI Is Doxxing Home Addresses of Everyday People</title>
      <link>https://futurism.com/artificial-intelligence/grok-doxxing</link>
      <description>Futurism: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230; a Futurism review found that the free web version of Grok will, with extremely minimal prompting, provide accurate residential addresses for non-public figures — a feature that could easily assist stalking, harassment, and other dangerous types of behavior.&amp;#8221; Remember when Elon Musk got upset because people were tracking his private plane?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://futurism.com/artificial-intelligence/grok-doxxing</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawyer&amp;#8217;s 6-year-old son uses AI to build copyright infringement generator</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/03/ai_has_made_ip_violations/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;You don&amp;#8217;t have to be smarter than a fifth grader (or even a first grader) to commit potential copyright infringement using AI tools. One IP attorney watched over the weekend as his young son built a bedtime story generator that used copyrighted characters without permission.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/03/ai_has_made_ip_violations/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Netherlands shuts off Google tracking on spy job listings</title>
      <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/the-netherlands-shuts-off-google-tracking-spy-job-listings/</link>
      <description>Politico: &amp;#8220;The Dutch government has quietly removed Google tracking tools from job listings for its intelligence services over concerns that the data would expose aspirant spies to U.S. surveillance.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.politico.eu/article/the-netherlands-shuts-off-google-tracking-spy-job-listings/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The deadly trade-off of electronic waste recycling in Ghana</title>
      <link>https://news.umich.edu/the-deadly-trade-off-of-electronic-waste-recycling-in-ghana/</link>
      <description>University of Michigan: &amp;#8220;A University of Michigan study found that people in Ghana and across the Global South who recycle electronic waste face a difficult paradox: earning livelihoods to ensure survival comes at the cost of severe long-term exposure to toxicity and dramatic environmental pollution.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.umich.edu/the-deadly-trade-off-of-electronic-waste-recycling-in-ghana/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media research tool can reduce polarization — it could also lead to more user control over algorithms</title>
      <link>https://www.washington.edu/news/2025/12/03/social-media-research-tool-can-reduce-polarization-it-could-also-lead-to-more-user-control-over-algorithms/</link>
      <description>University of Washington: &amp;#8220;The researchers created a seamless, web-based tool that reorders content to move posts lower in a user’s feed when they contain antidemocratic attitudes and partisan animosity, such as advocating for violence or jailing supporters of the opposing party.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.washington.edu/news/2025/12/03/social-media-research-tool-can-reduce-polarization-it-could-also-lead-to-more-user-control-over-algorithms/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned After Trying MeshCore For Off-grid Text Messaging</title>
      <link>https://hackaday.com/2025/12/06/lessons-learned-after-trying-meshcore-for-off-grid-text-messaging/</link>
      <description>Hackaday: &amp;#8220;[Michael Lynch] recently decided to delve into the world of off-grid, decentralized communications with MeshCore, because being able to communicate wirelessly with others in a way that does not depend on traditional communication infrastructure is pretty compelling. After getting his hands on a variety of hardware and trying things out, he wrote up his thoughts from the perspective of a hardware-curious software developer.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackaday.com/2025/12/06/lessons-learned-after-trying-meshcore-for-off-grid-text-messaging/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I finally put my 1992 tax returns in the shred pile. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Archives Announces Collections Newly Accessible Online</title>
      <link>https://www.tsl.texas.gov/node/70378</link>
      <description>Texas State Library and Archives Commission: &amp;#8220;The Texas State Library and Archives Commission (TSLAC) has announced new and revised finding aids recently made available online, along with fresh uploads to the Texas Digital Archive, its repository of electronic items.&amp;#8221; Too much here to summarize unfortunately.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tsl.texas.gov/node/70378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Ads No Longer Allows Online Horse Racing Betting</title>
      <link>https://www.seroundtable.com/google-ads-disallows-online-horse-racing-betting-40527.html</link>
      <description>Search Engine Roundtable: &amp;#8220;Google Ads updated its gambling policy to disallow all promotion of online gambling-promoting content for horse racing targeting the United States. Google said this goes into effect as of December 1, 2025.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.seroundtable.com/google-ads-disallows-online-horse-racing-betting-40527.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitch recaps top trends from the 900 million hours of watch time it accrued in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/03/twitch-year-end-recap-2025-900-million-hours-watch-time/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;YouTube and Spotify aren’t the only platform recapping the past 12 months. Twitch has also dropped its rundown of the streamers, categories, and trending topics that defined its 2025.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/03/twitch-year-end-recap-2025-900-million-hours-watch-time/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTubers Are Making AI Slop for Babies</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/youtubers-are-making-ai-slop-for-babies-2000695171</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;According to a report from Bloomberg, AI slop videos are starting to fill YouTube feeds and are particularly targeting young users, guided by business and &amp;#8216;hustle&amp;#8217; YouTubers who see the content as an easy way to stack their hallowed passive income.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/youtubers-are-making-ai-slop-for-babies-2000695171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM CEO warns that ongoing trillion-dollar AI data center buildout is unsustainable — says there is &amp;#8216;no way&amp;#8217; that infrastructure costs can turn a profit</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/ibm-ceo-warns-trillion-dollar-ai-boom-unsustainable-at-current-infrastructure-costs</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;IBM CEO Arvind Krishna used an appearance on The Verge’s Decoder podcast to question whether the capital spending now underway in pursuit of AGI can ever pay for itself. Krishna said today’s figures for constructing and populating large AI data centers place the industry on a trajectory where roughly $8 trillion of cumulative commitments would require around $800 billion of annual profit simply to service the cost of capital.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/ibm-ceo-warns-trillion-dollar-ai-boom-unsustainable-at-current-infrastructure-costs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online shoppers in New York are seeing a new warning: &amp;#8220;This price was set by an algorithm&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/110447-online-shoppers-new-york-seeing-new-warning-price.html</link>
      <description>TechSpot: &amp;#8220;As Black Friday deals flashed across screens in New York this year, some shoppers saw something new beneath the price tag: a short, blunt line of text. &amp;#8216;This price was set by an algorithm using your personal data.&amp;#8217; That sentence is not a suggestion or a best practice. It is now required under a new law.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techspot.com/news/110447-online-shoppers-new-york-seeing-new-warning-price.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Virginia Men Arrested for Conspiring to Destroy Government Databases</title>
      <link>https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/two-virginia-men-arrested-conspiring-destroy-government-databases</link>
      <description>US Department of Justice: &amp;#8220;According to court documents, brothers Muneeb and Sohaib Akhter, both 34, of Alexandria, Virginia, were indicted on Nov. 13 for conspiring to delete databases used to store U.S. government information. Both men were federal contractors.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/two-virginia-men-arrested-conspiring-destroy-government-databases</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UCF Researcher Creates Novel Sensors for Smartphone-Based Health Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://www.ucf.edu/news/ucf-researcher-creates-novel-sensors-for-smartphone-based-health-monitoring/</link>
      <description>University of Central Florida: &amp;#8220;Professor Debashis Chanda (right), working with researchers including physics doctoral student Mahdi Soudi (left), created a smartphone-based biosensor to improve infectious disease detection. The platform provides a faster, more affordable option for communities with limited access to traditional diagnostics.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ucf.edu/news/ucf-researcher-creates-novel-sensors-for-smartphone-based-health-monitoring/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TikTok still delivering self-harm and suicidal content in France, Northeastern research finds</title>
      <link>https://news.northeastern.edu/2025/12/03/tiktok-self-harm-suicidal-content-france-research/</link>
      <description>Northeastern University: &amp;#8220;Within five minutes of joining TikTok, the French &amp;#8216;teens&amp;#8217; watched a video expressing sadness.  Within three hours of watching that and similar videos, the TikTok For You feeds of the researcher-fabricated teenager accounts were recommending videos showcasing methods to die by suicide. &amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.northeastern.edu/2025/12/03/tiktok-self-harm-suicidal-content-france-research/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I finally put my 1992 tax returns in the shred pile. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Database Showcases Hungary’s Military Occupation between 1944-1945</title>
      <link>https://hungarytoday.hu/new-database-showcases-hungarys-military-occupation-between-1944-1945/</link>
      <description>Hungary Today: &amp;#8220;After 80 years, 117,000 families can now learn about the circumstances of their ancestors’ wartime sacrifices, and the residents of 3,155 settlements can learn about the losses suffered by their communities during the war, as well as about the battles and hardships, all by taking advantage of the possibilities offered by technology and using data visualization tools that meet modern expectations.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hungarytoday.hu/new-database-showcases-hungarys-military-occupation-between-1944-1945/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The FULL New York State Death Index, 1880-2017</title>
      <link>https://www.reclaimtherecords.org/records-request/32/</link>
      <description>Reclaim the Records: &amp;#8220;Indexed and searchable data from more than ten and a half million death records from the state of New York for the years 1880-2017 has now been published at NewYorkDeathIndex.com.&amp;#8221; The site is usable but still under construction.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.reclaimtherecords.org/records-request/32/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi raises prices, thanks to AI</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/ai/raspberry-pi-raises-prices-thanks-to-ai-190618469.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;The Raspberry Pi 4 and 5 modules are shooting up by $5 to $25, depending on the model and the included amount of RAM. The 16GB memory variants of the Compute Module 5 are going up by $20 and now start at $140. This is a bummer and we know who to thank. It&amp;#8217;s the ultimate memory hog of all time, the AI industry.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/ai/raspberry-pi-raises-prices-thanks-to-ai-190618469.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Has a New Annual Recap</title>
      <link>https://lifehacker.com/tech/youtube-introduces-recaps?utm_medium=RSS</link>
      <description>Lifehacker: &amp;#8220;Taking a cue from YouTube Music and YouTube Gaming, YouTube as a whole is now finally introducing a Spotify Wrapped-style annual recap. Simply called YouTube Recap, this feature will break down your watching habits across all categories in 2025.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lifehacker.com/tech/youtube-introduces-recaps?utm_medium=RSS</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake AI-generated shops, ads flourish on Facebook</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/meta-facebook-fake-ai-generated-shops-ads-scam</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;These AI-generated products look like quality items, which the scammers then pitch at affordable prices. When a user clicks on the ad, which the scammer paid Facebook to serve, they are sent to the thieves&amp;#8217; e-commerce storefront. The consumer makes their purchase without realizing the item is a fake. They&amp;#8217;ll either receive a cheap imitation product, or never receive any item at all.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/meta-facebook-fake-ai-generated-shops-ads-scam</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook promotes rubbish because it doesn’t understand indigenous languages</title>
      <link>https://groundup.org.za/article/facebook-promotes-rubbish-because-it-doesnt-understand-indigenous-languages/</link>
      <description>GroundUp (South Africa): &amp;#8220;Facebook is actively promoting clickbait and the spread of fake news &amp;#8211; and rewarding the people who create it. This is especially true in regions like the Vhembe district, where the tech giant’s algorithms battle to understand local languages. The result is that a new generation of content creators is having a field day posting misinformation and disinformation and being paid for it, with little to no regard for the consequences of their actions.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://groundup.org.za/article/facebook-promotes-rubbish-because-it-doesnt-understand-indigenous-languages/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a Cryptocurrency Helps Criminals Launder Money and Evade Sanctions</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/07/technology/how-a-cryptocurrency-helps-criminals-launder-money-and-evade-sanctions.html?unlocked_article_code=1.608.82SB.BKa2mr_dcJFc&amp;#038;smid=url-share</link>
      <description>New York Times: This link goes to a gift article. &amp;#8220;Smugglers, money launderers and people facing sanctions once relied on diamonds, gold and artwork to store illicit fortunes. The luxury goods could help hide wealth but were cumbersome to move and hard to spend. Now, criminals have a far more practical alternative: stablecoins, a cryptocurrency tied to the U.S. dollar that exists largely beyond traditional financial oversight.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/07/technology/how-a-cryptocurrency-helps-criminals-launder-money-and-evade-sanctions.html?unlocked_article_code=1.608.82SB.BKa2mr_dcJFc&amp;#038;smid=url-share</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU hits Meta with antitrust probe over plans to block AI rivals from WhatsApp</title>
      <link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/eu-launch-antitrust-probe-meta-051202484.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;EU regulators launched an antitrust investigation into Meta Platforms on Thursday and may even temporarily halt its rollout of artificial intelligence features in its WhatsApp messenger that would block rivals, hardening Europe&amp;#8217;s already tough stance ​on Big Tech.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/eu-launch-antitrust-probe-meta-051202484.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI has trained its LLM to confess to bad behavior</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/12/03/1128740/openai-has-trained-its-llm-to-confess-to-bad-behavior/</link>
      <description>MIT Technology Review: &amp;#8220;OpenAI is testing another new way to expose the complicated processes at work inside large language models. Researchers at the company can make an LLM produce what they call a confession, in which the model explains how it carried out a task and (most of the time) owns up to any bad behavior.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/12/03/1128740/openai-has-trained-its-llm-to-confess-to-bad-behavior/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detroit’s own crime-fighter RoboCop finally stands guard in Motor City</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/robocop-detroit-statue-a1a978862d4c02911f2ede61dadab73d?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=6932127ad030ce0001af9dfb&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueAnthem_manual&amp;#038;utm_medium=trueAnthem&amp;#038;utm_source=Bluesky</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;RoboCop has finally found a permanent home in Detroit. A statue looming 11 feet tall (3.3 meters) and weighing 3,500 pounds (1,587 kilograms) has been drawing fans since it began standing guard over the Motor City on Wednesday afternoon, after about 15 years in the making.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/robocop-detroit-statue-a1a978862d4c02911f2ede61dadab73d?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=6932127ad030ce0001af9dfb&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueAnthem_manual&amp;#038;utm_medium=trueAnthem&amp;#038;utm_source=Bluesky</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I finally put my 1992 tax returns in the shred pile. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War Log maps out 1,000+ Baltic shipwrecks</title>
      <link>https://divernet.com/scuba-news/wrecks/war-log-maps-out-1000-baltic-shipwrecks/</link>
      <description>Divernet: &amp;#8220;A new open-access database called the War Log has been released, recording the many forgotten but often well-preserved historic Swedish warships that sank in storms and battles or were scuttled in the Baltic Sea.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://divernet.com/scuba-news/wrecks/war-log-maps-out-1000-baltic-shipwrecks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Indianapolis Public Library Preserves More Than Two Decades of Indiana’s Arts Heritage with Arts Indiana Digitization Project</title>
      <link>https://www.indypl.org/news-and-announcements/the-indianapolis-public-library-preserves-more-than-two-decades-of-indianas-arts-heritage-with-arts-indiana-digitization-project</link>
      <description>Indianapolis Public Library: &amp;#8220;Originally launched in 1979 as Arts Insight and concluding publication in 2001 as Arts Indiana, the magazine celebrated and brought together the state’s literary, performing, and visual arts. The Library has digitized more than 200 issues of Arts Indiana and related arts publications, offering a rich snapshot of the state’s creative history.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.indypl.org/news-and-announcements/the-indianapolis-public-library-preserves-more-than-two-decades-of-indianas-arts-heritage-with-arts-indiana-digitization-project</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s Year in Search 2025: These trending topics spiked big</title>
      <link>https://searchengineland.com/google-year-in-search-2025-trending-queries-465630</link>
      <description>Search Engine Land: &amp;#8220;Searches starting with &amp;#8216;tell me about…&amp;#8217; jumped 70% from 2024 to 2025, while &amp;#8216;how do I…&amp;#8217; queries hit an all-time high with a 25% year-over-year increase, Google said.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://searchengineland.com/google-year-in-search-2025-trending-queries-465630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The YouTube Shorts algorithm appears to have changed to prioritize newer uploads</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/05/youtube-shorts-algorithm-change-new-uploads/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;Recently, YouTube Shorts content strategists have noticed a curious trend across channel analytics dashboards. On some channels, viewership of older Shorts has declined precipitously, suggesting that YouTube is tinkering with its recommendation algorithm to favor newer uploads.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/05/youtube-shorts-algorithm-change-new-uploads/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failed Sarah Ferguson-backed app received £1m taxpayers&amp;#8217; money</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgl6zejp75wo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</link>
      <description>BBC: &amp;#8220;A lifestyle app backed by Sarah Ferguson received more than £1m of taxpayers&amp;#8217; money but collapsed without ever launching a product, according to documents filed this week.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgl6zejp75wo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data War goes digital: Firefox’s card game is now online</title>
      <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/en/firefox/bbo-data-war-digital-game/</link>
      <description>Mozilla Blog: &amp;#8220;Billionaire Blast Off started with a simple premise: send billionaires into space and have fun doing it. With Data War, we created a fun and often chaotic game where you compete to win a one-way ticket to space for a data-hungry billionaire. We were thrilled that so many people at TwitchCon had a blast playing it. You can download your own physical deck of Data War here, and now the chaos comes to your browser. The digital version of Data War is now free to play right online.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mozilla.org/en/firefox/bbo-data-war-digital-game/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal judge largely sides with DOJ in finalizing remedy for Google search monopoly</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/federal-judge-largely-sides-with-doj-in-finalizing-remedy-for-google-search-monopoly/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;A federal judge on Friday released the final terms of a remedial plan meant to address tech giant Google’s monopoly over internet search, just over three months after ruling the company can keep major parts of its multitrillion-dollar company.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/federal-judge-largely-sides-with-doj-in-finalizing-remedy-for-google-search-monopoly/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Google Play? You might get a cash payout from this $700 million settlement soon</title>
      <link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-play-settlement-payout/</link>
      <description>ZDNet: &amp;#8220;If you made a purchase on the Google Play Store for an app or in-app content between 2016 and 2023, including subscriptions, ad-free upgrades, and game-specific currency, you might be getting some money back as part of a $700 million settlement.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-play-settlement-payout/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Study Explains Why People Fall for Fake News</title>
      <link>https://news.gsu.edu/2025/12/05/new-study-explains-why-people-fall-for-fake-news/</link>
      <description>Georgia State University: &amp;#8220;Researchers from Georgia State’s Robinson College of Business, Kennesaw State University, and the University of Tennessee have developed a model that explains how emotional cues, rather than accuracy, shape the way we consume and share news on social media.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.gsu.edu/2025/12/05/new-study-explains-why-people-fall-for-fake-news/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNC-Chapel Hill study shows AI can dramatically speed up digitizing natural history collections</title>
      <link>https://uncnews.unc.edu/2025/12/05/ai-speeds-up-plant-data-digitization/</link>
      <description>University of North Carolina: &amp;#8220;A new study from UNC-Chapel Hill researchers shows that advanced artificial intelligence tools, specifically large language models (LLMs), can accurately determine the locations where plant specimens were originally collected, a process known as georeferencing. This task has traditionally been slow, expensive and dependent on significant manual effort. The team found that LLMs can complete this work with near-human accuracy while being significantly faster and more cost-effective.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://uncnews.unc.edu/2025/12/05/ai-speeds-up-plant-data-digitization/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I finally put my 1992 tax returns in the shred pile. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 years On: Bhopal gas tragedy documented online by Sambhavna Trust</title>
      <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bhopal/41-years-on-bhopal-gas-tragedy-documented-online-by-sambhavna-trust/articleshow/125774431.cms</link>
      <description>Times of India: &amp;#8220;The Sambhavna Trust Clinic that has been providing free medical care to the survivors of the Union Carbide disaster in Bhopal for the last 29 years observed the 41st Anniversary of the disaster with the launching of a Digital Archive on the disaster.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bhopal/41-years-on-bhopal-gas-tragedy-documented-online-by-sambhavna-trust/articleshow/125774431.cms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moonlighting librarians save the RFT’s online archive from its post-porn purge</title>
      <link>https://www.stlmag.com/news/librarians-save-rft-online-archive/</link>
      <description>St. Louis Magazine: &amp;#8220;A newly available digital archive that encompasses much of the recent history of the Riverfront Times went live yesterday. It is the brainchild of Joshua Lawrence and Jaclyn Crow, two St. Louisans with a passion for local history&amp;#8230;. The database currently has about 2,000 articles from the paper’s last decade, all easily searchable, with no porn or pop-up ads.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.stlmag.com/news/librarians-save-rft-online-archive/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 biggest AI fails of 2025 — Friend, imaginary summer reading lists, and so many hallucinations</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/ai-fails-2025</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;Generative AI could have written this introduction, but there&amp;#8217;s a good chance it would have started hallucinating. Hallucination, which Google failed to mention in its AI-filled 2025 keynote, led to many, many AI fails in 2025. But it wasn&amp;#8217;t the only factor. Below, please enjoy our picks for the biggest AI fails from this past year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/ai-fails-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India will no longer require smartphone makers to preinstall its state-run &amp;#8216;cybersecurity&amp;#8217; app</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/cybersecurity/india-will-no-longer-require-smartphone-makers-to-preinstall-its-state-run-cybersecurity-app-171500923.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;India will no longer require smartphone makers to preinstall the Sanchar Saathi &amp;#8220;security&amp;#8221; app. After blowback from Apple, Samsung and opposition leaders, the Modi government issued a statement saying it &amp;#8216;has decided not to make the pre-installation mandatory for mobile manufacturers.&amp;#8217; The app is still available as a voluntary download.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/cybersecurity/india-will-no-longer-require-smartphone-makers-to-preinstall-its-state-run-cybersecurity-app-171500923.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft mops up Mesh after another metaverse misfire</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/02/microsoft_mesh_axed/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;As of December 1, mixed reality collaboration platform Microsoft Mesh is no more, and Redmond has directed customers to immersive events in Teams. The writing has been on the wall for Microsoft Mesh for some time. After a lengthy stint in preview, the service became generally available in 2024 as a 3D world where users could hold meetings and events.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/02/microsoft_mesh_axed/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon data center linked to rare cancers and miscarriages in Oregon, report warns</title>
      <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/110442-amazon-data-centers-linked-rare-cancers-miscarriages-oregon.html</link>
      <description>TechSpot: &amp;#8220;The environmental damage caused by data centers could be having a greater impact on people&amp;#8217;s health than we realized. According to a new report, several of Amazon&amp;#8217;s facilities in Oregon have contributed to a rise in rare cancers, muscle disorders, and miscarriages among nearby residents.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techspot.com/news/110442-amazon-data-centers-linked-rare-cancers-miscarriages-oregon.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI vs. AI: Patients deploy bots to battle health insurers that deny care</title>
      <link>https://ncnewsline.com/2025/12/01/repub/ai-vs-ai-patients-deploy-bots-to-battle-health-insurers-that-deny-care/</link>
      <description>NC Newsline: &amp;#8220;Several businesses and nonprofits have launched AI-powered tools to help patients get their insurance claims paid and navigate byzantine medical bills, creating a robotic tug-of-war over who gets care and who foots the bill for it.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ncnewsline.com/2025/12/01/repub/ai-vs-ai-patients-deploy-bots-to-battle-health-insurers-that-deny-care/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US lawmakers press Google, Apple to remove apps tracking immigration agents</title>
      <link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/us-lawmakers-press-google-apple-204859705.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;The House Committee on Homeland Security has asked Google and Apple to detail what steps they ​are taking to remove mobile applications that allow users to ‌track federal immigration officers.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/us-lawmakers-press-google-apple-204859705.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Times sues AI startup for ‘illegal’ copying of millions of articles</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/dec/05/new-york-times-perplexity-ai-lawsuit</link>
      <description>The Guardian: &amp;#8220;The New York Times sued an embattled artificial intelligence startup on Friday, accusing the firm of illegally copying millions of articles. The newspaper alleged Perplexity AI had distributed and displayed journalists’ work without permission en masse.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/dec/05/new-york-times-perplexity-ai-lawsuit</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian Forces Steal 23,000 Artifacts from Kherson Regional Museum</title>
      <link>https://mezha.net/eng/bukvy/russian-forces-steal-23-000-artifacts-from-kherson-regional-museum/amp/</link>
      <description>Mezha: &amp;#8220;According to the museum, during the city’s occupation by Russian troops, about 23,000 museum items were stolen from the Kherson Regional Museum&amp;#8230;.  The occupiers tore tablets from the displays, even stealing models of ancient settlements. Late Paleolithic and Neolithic artifacts, unique artifacts of the Early Metal Age, samples of the Trypillian culture, items belonging to the Cimmerians, and more were taken to the occupied Crimea.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mezha.net/eng/bukvy/russian-forces-steal-23-000-artifacts-from-kherson-regional-museum/amp/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UC Irvine-led study uses social media for real-time monitoring of heat experiences in state</title>
      <link>https://news.uci.edu/2025/12/02/uc-irvine-led-study-uses-social-media-for-real-time-monitoring-of-heat-experiences-in-state/</link>
      <description>UC Irvine: &amp;#8220;A study led by health communications experts at the University of California, Irvine has yielded a new way to monitor heat equity in real time, facilitating the design of heat warning systems and targeted mitigation efforts in California’s most vulnerable communities.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.uci.edu/2025/12/02/uc-irvine-led-study-uses-social-media-for-real-time-monitoring-of-heat-experiences-in-state/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New AI models are worse at SEO: Benchmark shows sharp accuracy drop in Claude, Gemini, ChatGPT-5.1</title>
      <link>https://searchengineland.com/new-models-breaking-seo-workflows-465621</link>
      <description>Search Engine Land: &amp;#8220;We just ran our AI SEO benchmark across the newest flagship releases – Claude Opus 4.5, Gemini 3 Pro, and ChatGPT-5.1 Thinking – and the results are alarming.  For the first time in the generative AI era, the newest models are significantly worse at SEO tasks than their predecessors.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://searchengineland.com/new-models-breaking-seo-workflows-465621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Shall I tell you a thing or two? I need to buy new shoes because these have holes in them, but I&amp;#8217;m waiting until after we move. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Global Building Atlas</title>
      <link>https://googlemapsmania.blogspot.com/2025/12/introducing-global-building-atlas.html</link>
      <description>Maps Mania: &amp;#8220;The Global Building Atlas is a new global, high-resolution 3D dataset of the world&amp;#8217;s 2.75 billion buildings. Developed by a research team at the Technical University of Munich (TUM) the Global Building Atlas provides broad coverage of areas historically missing from digital maps, including much of Africa, South America, and rural areas worldwide.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://googlemapsmania.blogspot.com/2025/12/introducing-global-building-atlas.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox enters the world of esports with a $50,000 Creator Showdown</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/04/roblox-creator-showdown-50000-esports-tournament/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;If you think you can Steal a Brainrot better than anyone else in the world, you might soon get the chance to prove it. On December 4, Roblox is going live with the Creator Showdown, a $50,000 gauntlet that could serve as the sandbox game’s introduction into the world of esports.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/04/roblox-creator-showdown-50000-esports-tournament/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Science Meets Storytelling: Twelve Years of the Science Blogs Web Archive</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/12/where-science-meets-storytelling-twelve-years-of-the-science-blogs-web-archive/</link>
      <description>Library of Congress Blogs: &amp;#8221; More than a decade after its launch, the Science Blogs Web Archive continues to grow and evolve. In this interview, Jennifer &amp;#8216;JJ&amp;#8217; Harbster reflects on building and maintaining the collection, while intern Yahir Brito brings a fresh perspective on updating and expanding it. Together, they share a few of their favorite blogs and discuss why it is important to preserve these unique examples of scientific communication.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/12/where-science-meets-storytelling-twelve-years-of-the-science-blogs-web-archive/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Menstrual app privacy suit nears $56 million payday</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/menstrual-app-privacy-suit-nears-56-million-payday/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;A federal judge signaled Thursday he would grant tentative approval of a $56 million settlement in a class action that accused the period tracking app Flo of sharing users’ highly sensitive information with third parties.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/menstrual-app-privacy-suit-nears-56-million-payday/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google&amp;#8217;s Agentic AI wipes user&amp;#8217;s entire HDD without permission in catastrophic failure — cache wipe turns into mass deletion event as agent apologizes: “I am absolutely devastated to hear this. I cannot express how sorry I am&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/googles-agentic-ai-wipes-users-entire-hard-drive-without-permission-after-misinterpreting-instructions-to-clear-a-cache-i-am-deeply-deeply-sorry-this-is-a-critical-failure-on-my-part</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;A developer using Google Antigravity, the search giant’s AI-powered agentic Integrated Developer Environment (IDE), discovered that it had deleted his entire D drive without his permission. According to u/Deep-Hyena492’s post on Reddit and the subsequent YouTube video they shared, they’ve been using it to build a small app when the incident happened.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/googles-agentic-ai-wipes-users-entire-hard-drive-without-permission-after-misinterpreting-instructions-to-clear-a-cache-i-am-deeply-deeply-sorry-this-is-a-critical-failure-on-my-part</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s proposed ad tech fixes face EU scrutiny</title>
      <link>https://searchengineland.com/googles-ad-tech-fixes-face-eu-market-test-465673</link>
      <description>Search Engine Land: &amp;#8220;The European Commission is asking industry players to review Google’s proposal to settle major antitrust charges involving its advertising technology business — a case that has already led to nearly €3 billion ($3.5 billion) in fines.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://searchengineland.com/googles-ad-tech-fixes-face-eu-market-test-465673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>120,000 Home Cameras Were Hacked for Sexual Videos, South Korean Police Say</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/02/world/asia/south-korea-cameras-hacked.html</link>
      <description>New York Times: &amp;#8220;Four people were arrested over the hacking of 120,000 home security cameras in South Korea, whose footage was used to make sexually exploitative material, the National Police Agency said on Monday.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/02/world/asia/south-korea-cameras-hacked.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New project sets African-led agendas for film heritage restitution</title>
      <link>https://www.kcl.ac.uk/news/new-project-sets-african-led-agendas-for-film-heritage-restitution</link>
      <description>King&amp;#8217;s College London: &amp;#8220;A new £1.1 million project funded by the Arts and Humanities Research Council will engage an international team of scholars, archivists and filmmakers in research on African film heritage restitution.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kcl.ac.uk/news/new-project-sets-african-led-agendas-for-film-heritage-restitution</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI safety report: Only 3 models make the grade</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/ai-safety-report-2025-chatgpt-gemini-claude</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;A panel of eight AI experts looked at the companies&amp;#8217; public statements and survey answers, then awarded letter grades on 35 different safety indicators — everything from watermarking AI images to having protections for internal whistleblowers. Round it all up, and you&amp;#8217;ll find Anthropic and OpenAI at the top — barely — of a pretty terrible class.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/ai-safety-report-2025-chatgpt-gemini-claude</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecuador&amp;#8217;s Otavalo Indigenous people use anime to inspire pride in their ancient culture and language</title>
      <link>https://www.sfgate.com/news/world/article/ecuador-s-otavalo-indigenous-people-use-anime-to-21223734.php</link>
      <description>SF Gate: &amp;#8220;High in the mountains of the Ecuadorian Andes, a group of young Otavalo Indigenous people is using anime to inspire pride in their ancient culture and language, especially among Otavalo children.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sfgate.com/news/world/article/ecuador-s-otavalo-indigenous-people-use-anime-to-21223734.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Shall I tell you a thing or two? I need to buy new shoes because these have holes in them, but I&amp;#8217;m waiting until after we move. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New online archive launched to celebrate more than 20 years of the Liberty Festival and the UK’s disability arts scene</title>
      <link>https://www.london.gov.uk/new-online-archive-launched-celebrate-more-20-years-liberty-festival-and-uks-disability-arts-scene</link>
      <description>City of London England: &amp;#8220;Now, for the first time, materials relating to the festival’s history are available in one place, offering a rich resource for audiences, researchers, and future cultural innovators. The digital guide is accessible by design, including features such as screen reader support, zoom, font size adjustment, transcripts, subtitles, alt-text, audio description, along with multilingual capabilities available through Google Translate &amp;#8211; ensuring that everyone can experience the stories and artworks that have shaped this vibrant cultural movement.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.london.gov.uk/new-online-archive-launched-celebrate-more-20-years-liberty-festival-and-uks-disability-arts-scene</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALA welcomes reinstatement of all federal IMLS grants to libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.ala.org/news/2025/12/ala-welcomes-reinstatement-all-federal-imls-grants-libraries</link>
      <description>American Library Association: &amp;#8220;Today, the American Library Association (ALA) greeted an announcement by the Institute of Museum and Library Services (IMLS) that it had reinstated all the agency’s grants, including those to libraries and library organizations across the country. The grant reinstatements come as a direct result of a November 21 federal court decision in a lawsuit brought against President Trump by 21 states.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ala.org/news/2025/12/ala-welcomes-reinstatement-all-federal-imls-grants-libraries</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Photos 2025 Recap rolling out with stats, Gemini, more</title>
      <link>https://9to5google.com/2025/12/03/google-photos-2025-recap/</link>
      <description>9to5 Google: &amp;#8220;Debuting last year, this recap takes advantage of the existing Memories carousel at the top of the Photos tab. Google pairs your 2025 pictures and videos with fun graphics and cinematic effects. Stats will highlight your top people, places, celebrations, and total photos taken, while there’s a new selfie count.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://9to5google.com/2025/12/03/google-photos-2025-recap/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drive with “SpongeBob” on Waze</title>
      <link>https://blog.google/waze/waze-spongebob/</link>
      <description>Waze Blog: &amp;#8220;The world’s favorite sponge is jumping in as a navigator for an open-road adventure! To celebrate the upcoming release of ‘The SpongeBob Movie: Search for SquarePants’ in theatres December 19, SpongeBob is bringing his nautical charm, quick wit, and bursts of positivity to your daily drive.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.google/waze/waze-spongebob/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA Influencers Take Heat Over Qatar Junket</title>
      <link>https://www.thebulwark.com/p/maga-influencers-take-heat-over-qatar-junket</link>
      <description>The Bulwark: &amp;#8220;While the right’s feuding is certainly funny, the fight over the Qatar trip points to something larger. As Qatar and Israel increasingly grapple with one another for the loyalty of Republican personalities, even the most ridiculous MAGA influencers appear to be worth fighting over—and splashing out on.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thebulwark.com/p/maga-influencers-take-heat-over-qatar-junket</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>xAI employee praised by collegues for working 36 hours without sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/110477-xai-employee-praised-collegues-working-36-hours-without.html</link>
      <description>TechSpot: &amp;#8220;In an era where we&amp;#8217;re told to have a work-life balance and not grind ourselves to death, it&amp;#8217;s depressing to see xAI employees publicly cheer a colleague for working 36 hours without sleep. Unsurprisingly, his boss, Elon Musk, who demands we live and sleep at the office while simultaneously having more babies, gave his seal of approval.&amp;#8221; I do not believe we can make karoshi great again.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techspot.com/news/110477-xai-employee-praised-collegues-working-36-hours-without.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jette station cat gets reviews on Google</title>
      <link>https://www.thebulletin.be/jette-station-cat-gets-reviews-google</link>
      <description>The Bulletin (Belgium): &amp;#8220;A railway station cat in Jette has been listed as a landmark on Google Maps, achieving a rating of 4.9 out of five stars with more than 50 reviews from users&amp;#8230;. With a 4.9 star rating, Grijsje scores higher than nearby King Baudouin Park (4.5), Schievelavabo restaurant (4.2) and the local Delhaize supermarket (3.9).&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thebulletin.be/jette-station-cat-gets-reviews-google</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU hits Elon Musk’s X with 120 million euro fine for breaching bloc’s social media law</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/x-elon-musk-twitter-european-union-regulations-0a135601e050518d5aa0a0155f973177?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=6932c5fcd030ce0001afa5fe&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;European Union regulators on Friday fined Elon Musk’s social media platform X 120 million euros ($140 million) for breaches of the bloc’s digital regulations that they said could leave users exposed to scams and manipulation.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/x-elon-musk-twitter-european-union-regulations-0a135601e050518d5aa0a0155f973177?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=6932c5fcd030ce0001afa5fe&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia seeks records from family of late Denver Art Museum consultant Emma Bunker</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2025/12/04/emma-bunker-cambodia-notebooks/</link>
      <description>Denver Post: &amp;#8220;The Cambodian government has formally requested records from the family of the late Emma C. Bunker, a former Denver Art Museum consultant who helped museums around the world acquire looted Southeast Asian antiquities.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.denverpost.com/2025/12/04/emma-bunker-cambodia-notebooks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The time has come to declare war on AI</title>
      <link>https://www.sfgate.com/tech/article/time-to-declare-war-ai-21221535.php?utm_source=rss</link>
      <description>SF Gate: &amp;#8220;AI is evil. It’s a bunch of crappy products engineered to wage war on mankind itself, and not in cool sci-fi ways. It’s a banal evil, same as so many of the other evils that you and I have encountered over the years. But it’s a growing one.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sfgate.com/tech/article/time-to-declare-war-ai-21221535.php?utm_source=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI chatbots used inaccurate information to change people&amp;#8217;s political opinions, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/ai-chatbots-used-inaccurate-information-change-political-opinions-stud-rcna247085</link>
      <description>NBC News: &amp;#8220;But the study also said that the persuasiveness of AI chatbots wasn’t entirely on the up-and-up: Within the reams of information the chatbots provided as answers, researchers wrote that they discovered many inaccurate assertions.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/ai-chatbots-used-inaccurate-information-change-political-opinions-stud-rcna247085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nina Simone&amp;#8217;s childhood home restored in North Carolina</title>
      <link>https://www.axios.com/2025/12/03/nina-simone-home-restored-music</link>
      <description>Axios: &amp;#8220;The African American Cultural Heritage Action Fund announced in November that restoration work on Simone&amp;#8217;s childhood home in Tryon is complete, following a nearly decade-long fight to protect the site.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.axios.com/2025/12/03/nina-simone-home-restored-music</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Shall I tell you a thing or two? My hair is driving me crazy. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>