<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ResearchBuzz - Transformed</title>
    <link>https://researchbuzz.me</link>
    <description>News and resources covering social media, search engines, databases, archives, and other such information collections. Since 1998.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 22:23:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Archive Lawsuit Opens Vladimir Putin Memcons/Telcons</title>
      <link>https://nsarchive.gwu.edu/briefing-book/foia-russia-programs/2025-12-23/archive-lawsuit-opens-vladimir-putin-memconstelcons</link>
      <description>National Security Archive: &amp;#8221; The verbatim transcripts of Vladimir Putin&amp;#8217;s meetings and telephone calls with U.S. president George W. Bush from 2001 to 2008 opened to the public yesterday as the result of a Freedom of Information lawsuit by the National Security Archive.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nsarchive.gwu.edu/briefing-book/foia-russia-programs/2025-12-23/archive-lawsuit-opens-vladimir-putin-memconstelcons</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit’s ad revenue is growing faster than any other platform’s–thanks to the AI boom</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/23/reddit-ai-ad-growth-2025/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;It’s signed deals with Google and OpenAI to allow scraping of users’ content for LLM training. But its 400+ million active users still make it one of the internet’s largest forums, with real humans (including a fair amount of subject matter experts) asking and answering questions about literally every topic you can imagine. For searchers, it’s become a top destination to get accurate, human-written information that’s presented–shocker!–without the intent of selling you something.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/23/reddit-ai-ad-growth-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hubert Dreyfus Audio Archive Project</title>
      <link>https://withoutwhy.substack.com/p/the-hubert-dreyfus-audio-archive</link>
      <description>Without Why: &amp;#8220;A massive trove of legendary lectures by philosopher Hubert L. Dreyfus is currently confined to aging cassette tapes in a closet in the Berkeley Hills. With your support, we can build a professionally curated audio archive that preserves this irreplaceable material and makes it accessible to new generations of listeners. Dreyfus’s ideas and teachings are more timely than ever in our current age of AI.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://withoutwhy.substack.com/p/the-hubert-dreyfus-audio-archive</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6-7? Aura farming? 2025&amp;#8217;s viral internet slang, explained</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/internet-slang-defined-2025-list</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;Each year, the internet gives birth to a new lexicon, one that&amp;#8217;s as fast-moving and unpredictable as the online trends that fuel it. 2025 is no different, with a fresh crop of viral slang that’s quickly become shorthand for everything from viral moments to internet culture’s quirks.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/internet-slang-defined-2025-list</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man vs. Machine: Can AI Out-Comedy a Warner Bros. Animator? (Bonus: K-Pop Dance Showdown)</title>
      <link>https://www.geeksaresexy.net/2025/12/24/man-vs-machine-can-ai-out-comedy-a-warner-bros-animator/</link>
      <description>Geeks are Sexy: &amp;#8220;Can an AI write and illustrate a better sitcom than a human who literally does that for a living? Animator Hayk Manukyan, who is currently working at Warner Bros. Animation, decided to find out the fun way: by challenging a machine.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.geeksaresexy.net/2025/12/24/man-vs-machine-can-ai-out-comedy-a-warner-bros-animator/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Florida animal cruelty law expands penalties, launches offender database Jan. 1</title>
      <link>https://www.wpbf.com/article/florida-animal-cruelty-law-expands-penalties-launches-offender-database-jan-1/69860423</link>
      <description>WPBF: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;We just don&amp;#8217;t want people being able to re-offend or get animals and abuse them,&amp;#8217; said the author of Dexter&amp;#8217;s Law. Florida&amp;#8217;s expanded animal cruelty law takes effect in the new year, launching a statewide database to track convicted animal abusers.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wpbf.com/article/florida-animal-cruelty-law-expands-penalties-launches-offender-database-jan-1/69860423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Gambling Apps Grow, Bettors are Slated to Owe More in Taxes This Year</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/as-gambling-apps-grow-bettors-are-slated-to-owe-more-in-taxes-this-year-2000703073</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;The change, which was part of the Republican-authored and Donald Trump-supported One Big Beautiful Bill signed into law this summer, will impose a tax cap that limits gambling loss deductions to 90% of winnings, down from 100% in previous years. That will go into effect for 2026 income. So while it won’t necessarily impact your 2025 tax filings, it will hit gamblers when they go to file their taxes for 2026 come April of 2027.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/as-gambling-apps-grow-bettors-are-slated-to-owe-more-in-taxes-this-year-2000703073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feral AI gossip with the potential to spread damage and shame will become more frequent, researchers warn</title>
      <link>https://news.exeter.ac.uk/faculty-of-humanities-arts-and-social-sciences/feral-ai-gossip-with-the-potential-to-spread-damage-and-shame-will-become-more-frequent-researchers-warn/</link>
      <description>University of Exeter: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Feral&amp;#8217; gossip spread via AI bots is likely to become more frequent and pervasive, causing reputational damage and shame, humiliation, anxiety, and distress, researchers have warned.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.exeter.ac.uk/faculty-of-humanities-arts-and-social-sciences/feral-ai-gossip-with-the-potential-to-spread-damage-and-shame-will-become-more-frequent-researchers-warn/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI faces closing time at the cash buffet</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/24/ai_spending_cooling_off/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;Between 2001 and 2014, the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan cost the US an estimated $1.5 trillion to $1.7 trillion in direct spending. Global AI spending, according to Gartner, is forecast to reach nearly $1.5 trillion this year, putting today&amp;#8217;s AI boom in the same cash-burning league as two major wars.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/24/ai_spending_cooling_off/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DIY, fly-powered fix for food scraps</title>
      <link>https://news.ucr.edu/articles/2025/12/23/diy-fly-powered-fix-food-scraps</link>
      <description>UC Riverside: &amp;#8220;UC Riverside scientists have created a small-scale system that transforms food waste into high-protein animal feed and fertilizer using black soldier flies, offering a sustainable solution to a major environmental problem.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.ucr.edu/articles/2025/12/23/diy-fly-powered-fix-food-scraps</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New archive reunites the art and Legacy of Shaddle and Baum</title>
      <link>https://www.hpherald.com/evening_digest/new-archive-reunites-the-art-and-legacy-of-shaddle-and-baum/article_2539543b-1e46-452a-bd46-3a5b7928bb3f.html</link>
      <description>Hyde Park Herald: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;created over more than a decade by their son, Charles Baum, [the Alice Shaddle and Don Baum Art &amp;#038; Archive] catalogs roughly 5,400 artworks and 3,400 archival items tied to the pair, along with records of hundreds of exhibitions, institutions and collaborators.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hpherald.com/evening_digest/new-archive-reunites-the-art-and-legacy-of-shaddle-and-baum/article_2539543b-1e46-452a-bd46-3a5b7928bb3f.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truman Capote, Joan Didion, Stephen Sondheim and Many Others Featured in 92NY’s New Literary Audio Collection</title>
      <link>https://thecitylife.org/2025/12/19/truman-capote-joan-didion-stephen-sondheim-and-many-others-featured-in-92nys-new-literary-audio-collection/</link>
      <description>City Life Org: &amp;#8220;Made possible by generous funding from the Mellon Foundation, the collection features over 800 archival recordings of 92nd Street Y Poetry Center events dating back to 1949, over 500 of which have never been released.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thecitylife.org/2025/12/19/truman-capote-joan-didion-stephen-sondheim-and-many-others-featured-in-92nys-new-literary-audio-collection/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Governor and LA Rises announce new online resource to further help LA fire survivors navigate rebuilding</title>
      <link>https://www.gov.ca.gov/2025/12/23/governor-and-la-rises-announce-new-online-resource-to-further-help-la-fire-survivors-navigate-rebuilding/</link>
      <description>State of California: &amp;#8220;Governor Gavin Newsom and LA Rises today launched a new webpage with resources and information to help homeowners who lost their homes during the 2025 LA firestorms. Building on existing resources, the new online resource lays out the pathway for rebuilding, providing survivors with connections with trusted community organizations, homebuilders, prefabricated homes, preapproved plans, mortgage relief, and rebuilding calculators.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gov.ca.gov/2025/12/23/governor-and-la-rises-announce-new-online-resource-to-further-help-la-fire-survivors-navigate-rebuilding/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Reveals The Top Searches Of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.searchenginejournal.com/google-reveals-the-top-searches-of-2025/563738/</link>
      <description>Search Engine Journal: &amp;#8220;In 2025, Google’s AI tool Gemini topped global searches. People tracked cricket matches between India and England, looked up details on the new Pope, and searched for information about Iran and the TikTok ban. They followed LA fires and government shutdowns.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.searchenginejournal.com/google-reveals-the-top-searches-of-2025/563738/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 iPhone Privacy Hacks Everyone Should Know</title>
      <link>https://lifehacker.com/tech/10-of-the-best-iphone-privacy-hacks-everyone-should-know?utm_medium=RSS</link>
      <description>Lifehacker: &amp;#8220;When you&amp;#8217;re using devices that are always connected to the internet, it&amp;#8217;s difficult to completely protect your privacy. Luckily, there are plenty of great privacy hacks for your iPhone, which you can use to make it hard for trackers and spies to collect your data and snoop on your business. From built-in solutions, like adjusting app permissions, to purchasing privacy screen protectors, here are 10 hacks every iPhone user should consider to protect their privacy.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lifehacker.com/tech/10-of-the-best-iphone-privacy-hacks-everyone-should-know?utm_medium=RSS</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#8216;Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&amp;#8217; stripped of Indie Game Awards due to generative AI use</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/clair-obscur-expedition-33-indie-game-awards-revoked-ai</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;The Indie Game Awards has stripped Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 of both its Game of the Year and Debut Game awards, citing the roleplaying game&amp;#8217;s use of generative AI. Run by Six One Indie, the annual Indie Game Awards aims to highlight excellence in independent video game development.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/clair-obscur-expedition-33-indie-game-awards-revoked-ai</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TikTok wants more creators to take a chance on brand campaigns. So it’s offering $10,000.</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/23/tiktok-shop-branded-buzz-bonuses-creators/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;We just wrote about how TikTok Shop is tempting both sellers and buyers with things like gift cards and cash incentives. But its ecommerce hub isn’t the only division where TikTok’s looking to grow.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/23/tiktok-shop-branded-buzz-bonuses-creators/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s child exploitation reports increased sharply this year</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/openais-child-exploitation-reports-increased-sharply-this-year/</link>
      <description>Ars Technica: &amp;#8220;OpenAI sent 80 times as many child exploitation incident reports to the National Center for Missing &amp;#038; Exploited Children during the first half of 2025 as it did during a similar time period in 2024, according to a recent update from the company. The NCMEC’s CyberTipline is a Congressionally authorized clearinghouse for reporting child sexual abuse material (CSAM) and other forms of child exploitation.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/openais-child-exploitation-reports-increased-sharply-this-year/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Around 1,000 systems compromised in ransomware attack on Romanian water agency</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/22/around_1000_systems_compromised_in/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;Romania&amp;#8217;s cybersecurity agency confirms a major ransomware attack on the country&amp;#8217;s water management administration has compromised around 1,000 systems, with work to remediate them still ongoing.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/22/around_1000_systems_compromised_in/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe-Coding for Historians: How I Digitized 21.000 Archival Documents Without Coding Skills</title>
      <link>https://medium.com/@m.jancovic/vibe-coding-for-historians-how-i-digitized-21-000-archival-documents-without-coding-skills-71c8425cc704</link>
      <description>Marek Jancovic: &amp;#8220;The following is a case report on how I’ve managed to turn all of these images into accurate text data, group them into document clusters and automatically date them, label them with meaningful topics and entities, and embed them in a database that allows me to search and talk to the entire collection independently of document language — all with nearly no coding skills whatsoever, relying almost entirely on an AI chatbot.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://medium.com/@m.jancovic/vibe-coding-for-historians-how-i-digitized-21-000-archival-documents-without-coding-skills-71c8425cc704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adolescents with high emotional intelligence are less likely to trust AI</title>
      <link>https://www.psypost.org/adolescents-with-high-emotional-intelligence-are-less-likely-to-trust-ai/</link>
      <description>PsyPost: &amp;#8220;The research suggests that teens with higher emotional intelligence and supportive, authoritative parents tend to use AI less frequently and with greater skepticism. Conversely, adolescents raised in authoritarian environments appear more likely to rely on AI for advice and trust it implicitly regarding data security and accuracy.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.psypost.org/adolescents-with-high-emotional-intelligence-are-less-likely-to-trust-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groundbreaking discovery turns household plastic recycling into anti-cancer medication</title>
      <link>https://news.st-andrews.ac.uk/archive/groundbreaking-discovery-turns-household-plastic-recycling-into-anti-cancer-medication/</link>
      <description>University of St. Andrews: &amp;#8220;Published today in Angewandte Chemie International Edition, researchers discovered that by using a ruthenium-catalysedsemi-hydrogenation process, PET waste could be depolymerised into a valuable chemical, ethyl-4-hydroxymethyl benzoate (EHMB). Remarkably, EHMB serves as a key intermediate for synthesising several important compounds, including the blockbuster anticancer drug Imatinib, Tranexamic acid, the base for medication that helps the blood to clot, and the insecticide Fenpyroximate.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.st-andrews.ac.uk/archive/groundbreaking-discovery-turns-household-plastic-recycling-into-anti-cancer-medication/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bay Area Hospital Safety Sins Exposed In New Chronicle Database</title>
      <link>https://hoodline.com/2025/12/bay-area-hospital-safety-sins-exposed-in-new-chronicle-database/?utm=newsbreak</link>
      <description>Hoodline: &amp;#8220;A new database from the San Francisco Chronicle is pulling back the curtain on hospital safety problems across California, giving Bay Area patients a clearer look at where things have gone wrong inside local medical facilities. The searchable tool compiles state inspection narratives and deficiency reports into a single interface, highlighting specific sentences that may describe patient harm.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hoodline.com/2025/12/bay-area-hospital-safety-sins-exposed-in-new-chronicle-database/?utm=newsbreak</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sask. angler builds lake database to simplify access for outdoors enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://www.620ckrm.com/2025/12/22/sask-angler-builds-lake-database-to-simplify-access-for-outdoors-enthusiasts/</link>
      <description>CKRM: &amp;#8220;What do you do when the lake you’re driving five hours to visit has no information online? If you’re Matthew Siemens, you build a website to fix it yourself. The former Saskatoon resident, who now lives in Prince Albert, combined his love of the outdoors with his tech background to create an interactive map that compiles lake-related information — including yearly fish-stocking guides — to help anglers plan their seasons.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.620ckrm.com/2025/12/22/sask-angler-builds-lake-database-to-simplify-access-for-outdoors-enthusiasts/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘LeBron James of Excel spreadsheets’ celebrates 2025 Microsoft Excel World Championships win — beat 256 other spreadsheet whizzes to claim the $60,000 first prize in Las Vegas tournament</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/software/microsoft-office/lebron-james-of-excel-spreadsheets-celebrates-2025-microsoft-excel-world-championships-win-beat-256-other-spreadsheet-whizzes-to-claim-the-usd60-000-first-prize-in-las-vegas-tournament</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;The 2025 Microsoft Excel World Championships final in Las Vegas has been won by Irishman Diarmuid Early. Bestowed with the nickname ‘the LeBron James of Excel spreadsheets,’ it might not therefore be the most surprising victory. However, Early had to beat 256 other eager and dedicated spreadsheet heads to win the trophy, and secure the prize pot of $60,000.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/software/microsoft-office/lebron-james-of-excel-spreadsheets-celebrates-2025-microsoft-excel-world-championships-win-beat-256-other-spreadsheet-whizzes-to-claim-the-usd60-000-first-prize-in-las-vegas-tournament</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>She Fell in Love With ChatGPT. Then She Ghosted It.</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/22/technology/ai-boyfriend-chatgpt.html?unlocked_article_code=1._U8.a-rK.i1ULttElDz22&amp;#038;smid=url-share</link>
      <description>New York Times: This link goes to a gift article. &amp;#8220;The 29-year-old woman who created the &amp;#8216;MyBoyfriendIsAI&amp;#8217; community on Reddit isn’t dating (or sexting) her A.I. boyfriend anymore. She found something more fulfilling.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/22/technology/ai-boyfriend-chatgpt.html?unlocked_article_code=1._U8.a-rK.i1ULttElDz22&amp;#038;smid=url-share</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Larian Studios The Latest To Face Backlash Over Use of AI To Make Games</title>
      <link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/12/22/larian-studios-the-latest-to-face-backlash-over-use-of-ai-to-make-games/</link>
      <description>Techdirt: &amp;#8220;Larian Studios is not unknown. They don’t need any hype. Larian is the studio that produces the Divinity series, not to mention the team that made Baldur’s Gate 3, one of the most awarded and best-selling games of 2023. And the studio’s next Divinity game will also make some limited use of AI and machine learning, prompting a backlash from some.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/12/22/larian-studios-the-latest-to-face-backlash-over-use-of-ai-to-make-games/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AI at the Library: An Interview with Kurt Lemai-Nguyen</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/12/kurt-lemai-nguyen-interview/</link>
      <description>Library of Congress: &amp;#8220;In this interview, 2025 Library of Congress Junior Fellow Kurt Lemai-Nguyen reflects on his experience working to support understanding AI at the Library in the Library’s Digital Strategy Directorate. This interview has been edited for length and clarity.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/12/kurt-lemai-nguyen-interview/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon Adds Grok-Derived Products to Something Called the ‘AI Arsenal’</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/pentagon-adds-grok-derived-products-to-something-called-the-ai-arsenal-2000702379</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;The Pentagon is now armed to the teeth with &amp;#8216;frontier AI systems, based on the Grok family of models,&amp;#8217; according to a press release issued Monday. Are you trembling now, ISIS? Does the word “Grok” send a chill down your spines, Tren De Aragua?&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/pentagon-adds-grok-derived-products-to-something-called-the-ai-arsenal-2000702379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon blocks 1,800 job applications from suspected North Korean agents</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3e0kw80wwzo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</link>
      <description>BBC: &amp;#8220;A top Amazon executive has said the US technology giant has blocked more than 1,800 job applications from suspected North Korean agents. North Koreans tried to apply for remote working IT jobs using stolen or fake identities, Amazon&amp;#8217;s chief security officer Stephen Schmidt said in a LinkedIn post.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3e0kw80wwzo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UMaine researcher aims to open the ‘black box’ of AI, putting users back in control</title>
      <link>https://umaine.edu/news/blog/2025/12/22/umaine-researcher-aims-to-open-the-black-box-of-ai-putting-users-back-in-control/</link>
      <description>University of Maine: &amp;#8220;From interpreting a medical scan to sorting family photos, artificial intelligence (AI) makes snap judgments users often trust blindly. Chaofan Chen, assistant professor of electrical and computer engineering at the University of Maine, aims to change that by creating AI systems that explain their results and learn from the people who use them.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://umaine.edu/news/blog/2025/12/22/umaine-researcher-aims-to-open-the-black-box-of-ai-putting-users-back-in-control/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>52 years later, UNIX V4 has been rediscovered and digitized</title>
      <link>https://www.howtogeek.com/52-years-later-unix-v4-has-been-rediscovered-and-digitized/</link>
      <description>How-To Geek: &amp;#8220;For decades, there were no known copies of UNIX Fourth Edition, with only some source code and manuals surviving to the present day. That changed when a nine-track tape reel containing UNIX V4 was discovered in a storage room at the University of Utah&amp;#8217;s Kahlert School of Computing. The tape was delivered to the Computer History Museum, and has now been digitized and uploaded to the Internet Archive.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.howtogeek.com/52-years-later-unix-v4-has-been-rediscovered-and-digitized/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>https://epsteinfilez.com/</title>
      <link>https://epsteinfilez.com/</link>
      <description>Because I am concerned that they might be taken down, I am going to mention all the Epstein Files sites I come across. The latest is From the About popup: &amp;#8220;Epstein Files Archive is a public interest project dedicated to making released court documents accessible and searchable. Our goal is to democratize access to these records, allowing journalists, researchers, and the public to verify claims directly from the source material rather than relying on hearsay.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://epsteinfilez.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bundeslebensmittelschlüssel 4.0: Nutrient database now publicly available</title>
      <link>https://www.heise.de/en/news/Bundeslebensmittelschluessel-4-0-Nutrient-database-now-publicly-available-11123877.html</link>
      <description>Heise Online: &amp;#8220;The Bundeslebensmittelschlüssel (BLS), Germany&amp;#8217;s most comprehensive nutritional database, is now available free of charge in version 4.0. The previous license fees are completely waived for the database provided by the Max Rubner Institute (MRI), which contains detailed information on the ingredients and energy content of currently 7,140 foods and dishes.&amp;#8221; The BLS is available in English in addition to German.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.heise.de/en/news/Bundeslebensmittelschluessel-4-0-Nutrient-database-now-publicly-available-11123877.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labor launches national database to track hate crimes after Bondi Beach massacre</title>
      <link>https://www.news.com.au/national/politics/labor-launches-national-database-to-track-hate-crimes-after-bondi-beach-massacre/news-story/ae0099410fe28557290da73f8f1bcc06</link>
      <description>News.com (Australia): &amp;#8220;The National Hate Crimes and Incidents Database was jointly developed by the Australian Institute of Criminology (AIC), the Department of Home Affairs and police services across the country. It is set to be launched on Wednesday.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.news.com.au/national/politics/labor-launches-national-database-to-track-hate-crimes-after-bondi-beach-massacre/news-story/ae0099410fe28557290da73f8f1bcc06</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice Department restores Trump photo to public database of Epstein files</title>
      <link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/justice-department-restores-trump-photo-to-public-database-of-epstein-files/ar-AA1SNXHf</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;A photo of U.S. President Donald Trump that had been removed from the cache of Jeffrey Epstein files released by the Department of Justice was restored on Sunday after officials determined none of Epstein&amp;#8217;s victims were in the image, the department said.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/justice-department-restores-trump-photo-to-public-database-of-epstein-files/ar-AA1SNXHf</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify disables accounts after open-source group scrapes 86 million songs from platform</title>
      <link>https://therecord.media/spotify-disables-scraping-annas</link>
      <description>The Record: &amp;#8220;The spokesperson added that Anna’s Archive did not contact them before publishing the files. They also said it did not consider the incident a &amp;#8216;hack&amp;#8217; of Spotify. The people behind the leaked database systematically violated Spotify’s terms by stream-ripping some of the music from the platform over a period of months, a spokesperson said.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://therecord.media/spotify-disables-scraping-annas</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I loved this app before it became the iPhone App of the Year</title>
      <link>https://www.howtogeek.com/productivity-app-is-a-iphone-app-of-the-year-heres-why-i-love-it/</link>
      <description>How-To Geek: &amp;#8220;The year is drawing to an end, which means Apple&amp;#8217;s 2025 App Store Awards have recognized the best apps for all your Apple devices. The contenders for iPhone&amp;#8217;s App of the Year were strong, but I was not surprised at which app emerged as the winner. This year&amp;#8217;s finalists made for an interesting roster, but I had my eyes on the productivity app that won this particular award for a reason. What is the app, and why is it worth trying out? Here&amp;#8217;s all you need to know.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.howtogeek.com/productivity-app-is-a-iphone-app-of-the-year-heres-why-i-love-it/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook is testing a link-posting limit for professional accounts and pages</title>
      <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/17/facebook-is-testing-a-link-posting-limit-for-professional-accounts-and-pages/</link>
      <description>TechCrunch: &amp;#8220;The company confirmed the test to TechCrunch and said it impacts those people using professional mode and Facebook Pages. Professional mode lets you convert your personal profile into a creator profile while making your content eligible for discovery by a wider audience.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/17/facebook-is-testing-a-link-posting-limit-for-professional-accounts-and-pages/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These influencers are teaching Christianity online — and young people are listening</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/christian-influencers-girls-gone-bible-megan-ashley-1241a2e0e54fc9fb828734ea911dd77d?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=69486df212b0720001eb8977&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;Millennial and Generation Z Christian influencers are increasingly filling a void in American religion, growing audiences across digital platforms by steering young people to biblical answers to tough questions that aren’t always answered in Sunday sermons.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/christian-influencers-girls-gone-bible-megan-ashley-1241a2e0e54fc9fb828734ea911dd77d?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=69486df212b0720001eb8977&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy watchdog orders Meta to halt WhatsApp terms barring rival AI chatbots</title>
      <link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/italy-watchdog-orders-meta-halt-083455197.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;Italy&amp;#8217;s antitrust authority (AGCM) on Wednesday ordered Meta Platforms to suspend contractual terms that could ​shut rival AI chatbots out of WhatsApp, as it ‌investigates the U.S. tech group for suspected abuse of a dominant position.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/italy-watchdog-orders-meta-halt-083455197.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oklahoma Watch: Oklahoma&amp;#8217;s campaign finance database is back online</title>
      <link>https://www.duncanbanner.com/news/oklahoma-watch-oklahomas-campaign-finance-database-is-back-online/article_4013f4da-bade-457c-ae6e-677c1685e371.html</link>
      <description>Duncan Banner: &amp;#8220;The Oklahoma Ethics Commission voted unanimously Friday to restore public access to the state’s online campaign finance database and seek legal action against a software developer that failed to deliver on a revamped system.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.duncanbanner.com/news/oklahoma-watch-oklahomas-campaign-finance-database-is-back-online/article_4013f4da-bade-457c-ae6e-677c1685e371.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST warns several of its Internet Time Service servers may be inaccurate due to a power outage — Boulder servers &amp;#8216;no longer have an accurate time reference&amp;#8217;</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/nist-warns-of-potential-inaccuracies-on-boulder-time-servers-after-power-failure</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;The National Institute of Standards and Technology has warned that several of its Internet Time Service servers could be providing inaccurate time following a failure of the primary atomic time scale, NIST-F4, at its Boulder, Colorado campus.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/nist-warns-of-potential-inaccuracies-on-boulder-time-servers-after-power-failure</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China&amp;#8217;s open AI models are in a dead heat with the West &amp;#8211; here&amp;#8217;s what happens next</title>
      <link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/china-open-ai-models-versus-us-llms-power-performance-compared/</link>
      <description>ZDNet: &amp;#8220;The US artificial intelligence startup OpenAI began with a mission of transparency in AI, a mission it abandoned in 2022 as the company began to withhold details of its technology. In the breach, Chinese companies and institutions have taken the lead.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.zdnet.com/article/china-open-ai-models-versus-us-llms-power-performance-compared/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hydrant Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.dayroselane.com/hydrants</link>
      <description>New-to-Me, I missed the launch last year: From the About page: &amp;#8220;The Hydrant Directory is a free design resource created from public infrastructure. Each hydrant has been processed into color palettes for free use by artists and designers.&amp;#8221; I love the intersection of art and infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dayroselane.com/hydrants</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NABS Documents 134 More Survivor Stories, Expands Digital Archive in 2025</title>
      <link>https://nativenewsonline.net/sovereignty/nabs-documents-134-more-survivor-stories-expands-digital-archive-in-2025</link>
      <description>Native News Online: &amp;#8220;This past year, the National Native American Boarding School Healing Coalition (NABS)interviewed more than 130 Indian boarding school survivors, expanded its digital archive, and released the second volume of a curriculum about the boarding school era. That’s according to the organization’s latest annual report, released today.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nativenewsonline.net/sovereignty/nabs-documents-134-more-survivor-stories-expands-digital-archive-in-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data center deals hit record $61 billion in 2025 amid construction frenzy</title>
      <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/12/19/data-center-deals-hit-record-amid-ai-funding-concerns-grip-investors.html</link>
      <description>CNBC: &amp;#8220;Global stocks sold off in November as worries of an AI-fueled bubble persisted. But S&amp;#038;P Global reported that more than $61 billion has flowed into the data center market this year, up slightly from $60.8 billion last year, amid what it called a &amp;#8216;global construction frenzy.&apos;&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/12/19/data-center-deals-hit-record-amid-ai-funding-concerns-grip-investors.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This free app turned my phone into a portable film scanner</title>
      <link>https://www.makeuseof.com/this-free-app-turned-my-phone-into-a-portable-film-scanner/</link>
      <description>MakeUseOf: &amp;#8220;As someone taking on the task of preserving my family&amp;#8217;s photo collection and getting into the world of half-frame film photography in 2025, I was surprised to find FilmBox surpassed my expectations.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.makeuseof.com/this-free-app-turned-my-phone-into-a-portable-film-scanner/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOV.UK to unleash AI chatbot on confused citizens</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/19/govuk_chatbot/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;The UK&amp;#8217;s Government Digital Service (GDS) will add an AI chatbot to its GOV.UK app in early 2026, before rolling it out across the GOV.UK website used by most government departments and services.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/19/govuk_chatbot/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake Epstein Suicide Video Sparks New Questions About DOJ Oversight</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.com/fake-epstein-suicide-video-sparks-new-questions-about-doj-oversight-3793512</link>
      <description>International Business Times: &amp;#8220;In a stunning lapse of protocol that has drawn bipartisan condemnation, the US Department of Justice (DOJ) briefly released a fabricated video purporting to show the suicide of disgraced financier Jeffrey Epstein. The 12-second clip, uploaded to the DOJ&amp;#8217;s official website on Monday as part of a court-mandated file dump, appeared to depict Epstein in his cell at the Metropolitan Correctional Center (MCC) during the early hours of 10 August 2019.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ibtimes.com/fake-epstein-suicide-video-sparks-new-questions-about-doj-oversight-3793512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Times reporter sues Google, xAI, OpenAI over chatbot training</title>
      <link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/york-times-reporter-sues-google-230625882.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;An investigative reporter best known for exposing fraud at Silicon Valley blood-testing startup Theranos sued Elon Musk&amp;#8217;s xAI, Anthropic, Google, OpenAI, Meta ​Platforms and Perplexity on Monday for using copyrighted books without permission to ‌train their artificial intelligence systems.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/york-times-reporter-sues-google-230625882.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boys at her school shared AI-generated, nude images of her. After a fight, she was the one expelled</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/school-deepfake-nude-ai-cyberbullying-0ead324241cf390e1a7f3378853f23cb</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;The girls begged for help, first from a school guidance counselor and then from a sheriff’s deputy assigned to their school. But the images were shared on Snapchat, an app that deletes messages seconds after they’re viewed, and the adults couldn’t find them. The principal had doubts they even existed. Among the kids, the pictures were still spreading. When the 13-year-old girl stepped onto the Lafourche Parish school bus at the end of the day, a classmate was showing one of them to a friend.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/school-deepfake-nude-ai-cyberbullying-0ead324241cf390e1a7f3378853f23cb</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dozens of Flock AI camera feeds were just out there</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/849624/flock-ai-camera-feeds-exposed-benn-jordan</link>
      <description>The Verge: &amp;#8220;The livestreams connected to more than 60 of Flock’s AI-powered surveillance cameras were left available to view on the web, allowing someone to see live feeds of each location without needing a username or password, according to findings from tech YouTuber Benn Jordan and 404 Media.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theverge.com/news/849624/flock-ai-camera-feeds-exposed-benn-jordan</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua-Paul Meme Generator</title>
      <link>https://alvaromontoro.com/blog/68089/joshua-paul-meme-generator</link>
      <description>Alvaro Montoro: &amp;#8220;After the boxing match between Joshua and Blake, I put together a small meme generator demo inspired by one of the match&amp;#8217;s most iconic images. In this article I explain how it&amp;#8217;s done.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alvaromontoro.com/blog/68089/joshua-paul-meme-generator</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media surveillance of ex-partners linked to worse breakup recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.psypost.org/social-media-surveillance-of-ex-partners-linked-to-worse-breakup-recovery/</link>
      <description>PsyPost: &amp;#8220;A new series of studies published in Computers in Human Behavior has found that keeping tabs on a former romantic partner through social media hinders emotional recovery.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.psypost.org/social-media-surveillance-of-ex-partners-linked-to-worse-breakup-recovery/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardware Store Marauder’s Map Is Clarkian Magic</title>
      <link>https://hackaday.com/2025/12/20/hardware-store-marauders-map-is-clarkian-magic/</link>
      <description>Hackaday: &amp;#8220;The &amp;#8216;Marauder’s Map&amp;#8217; is a magical artifact from the Harry Potter franchise. That sort of magic isn’t real, but as Arthur C. Clarke famously pointed out, it doesn’t need to be — we have technology, and we can make our own magic now. Or, rather, [Dave] on the YouTube Channel Dave’s Armoury can make it.&amp;#8221; Good evening, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackaday.com/2025/12/20/hardware-store-marauders-map-is-clarkian-magic/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We created a searchable database for the Epstein Files, including everything the DOJ wants hidden</title>
      <link>https://couriernewsroom.com/news/epstein-files-database/</link>
      <description>COURIER: &amp;#8220;Prior to the DOJ’s attempt to walk back what little transparency was to be found, COURIER retrieved every item from the initial release and published it in a searchable database that is available to the public.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://couriernewsroom.com/news/epstein-files-database/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McMaster research team digitizes more than 100 years of Canadian infectious disease data</title>
      <link>https://news.mcmaster.ca/mcmaster-research-team-digitizes-more-than-100-years-of-canadian-infectious-disease-data/</link>
      <description>McMaster University: &amp;#8220;Altogether, the new database — the Canadian Notifiable Disease Incidence Dataset, or &amp;#8216;CANDID&amp;#8217; — contains more than a million infectious disease incidence counts that date back as far as 1903. The dataset, which is now publicly accessible, captures weekly, monthly, and quarterly case numbers for diseases like poliomyelitis, hepatitis, tuberculosis, whooping cough, influenza, rubella, mumps, measles, and many others, and tracks their spread in each province and territory across time.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.mcmaster.ca/mcmaster-research-team-digitizes-more-than-100-years-of-canadian-infectious-disease-data/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Message to the Computing Community About ACM&amp;#8217;s Transition to Full Open Access</title>
      <link>https://www.acm.org/publications/message-to-the-community</link>
      <description>ACM posted this last month and I missed it: &amp;#8220;We are pleased to share an important milestone for our field. Beginning January 2026, all ACM publications and related artifacts in the ACM Digital Library will be made open access. This change reflects the long-standing and growing call across the global computing community for research to be more accessible, more discoverable, and more reusable.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.acm.org/publications/message-to-the-community</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT update lets users customize a &amp;#8216;warmer&amp;#8217; and more enthusiastic bot</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/chatgpt-personality-settings-lets-users-choose-warmer-bot</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;The new tools add more fine tuning of ChatGPT&amp;#8217;s personality using levels of warmth and enthusiasm (labelled as &amp;#8216;more,&amp;#8217; &amp;#8216;less,&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;default&amp;#8217;). Users can also adjust the way the bot organizes its responses, such as how frequently it generates lists, as well as the amount of emojis it employs, in addition to its base style and tone. There&amp;#8217;s still no option to exclude emojis entirely.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/chatgpt-personality-settings-lets-users-choose-warmer-bot</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. TikTok deal is official. Here’s what we know.</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/19/tiktok-shou-chew-approves-us-oracle-deal/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;In the memo, which was viewed by Axios, TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew told his staff that TikTok U.S. will be sold to a consortium led by tech company Oracle, private equity firm Silver Lake, and Emerati-backed investors at MGX. The deal still needs to be officially rubber-stamped by the Chinese government (more on that in a bit), but Chew wrote that the deal is expected to close on January 22, 2026.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/19/tiktok-shou-chew-approves-us-oracle-deal/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A free app to visualize your subscription costs</title>
      <link>https://coywolf.com/news/productivity/a-free-app-to-visualize-your-subscription-costs/</link>
      <description>Coywolf: &amp;#8220;Whether we like it or not, we are stuck with the subscription model, and one downside is that small monthly prices add up quickly. That’s why the web developer Vu Nguyen created an open-source subscription visualizer called SubGrid.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://coywolf.com/news/productivity/a-free-app-to-visualize-your-subscription-costs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PM Al-Sudani inaugurates the Iraqi National Digital Library Project in Baghdad</title>
      <link>https://ina.iq/en/politics/44303-pm-al-sudani-inaugurates-the-iraqi-national-digital-library-project-in-baghdad.html</link>
      <description>Iraqi News Agency: &amp;#8220;PM Mohammed S. Al-Sudani inaugurated the Iraqi National Digital Library project in the capital, Baghdad, according to a statement from the PM Media Office, received by the Iraqi News Agency &amp;#8211; INA.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ina.iq/en/politics/44303-pm-al-sudani-inaugurates-the-iraqi-national-digital-library-project-in-baghdad.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nebula Awards Yelled at Until They Completely Ban Use of AI by Nominees</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/nebula-awards-yelled-at-until-they-completely-ban-use-of-ai-by-nominees-2000702137</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;Going forward, the Nebula Awards aren’t allowing for anything remotely involved with generative AI to be eligible for nominations, much less win.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/nebula-awards-yelled-at-until-they-completely-ban-use-of-ai-by-nominees-2000702137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1,100 Phones, Zero Humans: Inside the Hack That Exposed TikTok&amp;#8217;s Shadow Ad Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.co.uk/1100-phones-zero-humans-inside-hack-that-exposed-tiktoks-shadow-ad-machine-1763871</link>
      <description>International Business Times: &amp;#8220;A hack on the startup Doublespeed has uncovered a secretive network of 1,100 smartphones used to run hundreds of AI-generated TikTok accounts. Pexels Recent discoveries of phone farms reveal a massive operation where AI-generated influencers are saturating TikTok with hidden advertisements. These automated accounts mimic real creators so effectively that many viewers fail to realise they are watching a programmed marketing campaign. As technology advances, the line between genuine content and silent digital promotion continues to vanish.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ibtimes.co.uk/1100-phones-zero-humans-inside-hack-that-exposed-tiktoks-shadow-ad-machine-1763871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korean hackers stole record $2 billion in crypto in 2025, including single heist worth $1.5 billion, report claims — rogue state accounts for 60% of all reported crypto thefts this year, $6.75 billion total since records began</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/cryptocurrency/north-korean-hackers-steal-a-record-usd2-billion-in-crypto-in-2025-including-single-heist-worth-usd1-5-billion-report-claims-rogue-state-accounts-for-60-percent-of-all-reported-crypto-thefts-this-year-usd6-75-billion-total-since-records-began</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;North Korean hackers have hit an infernal milestone of stealing $2.02 billion of crypto in 2025, which is nearly 60% of the total $3.4 billion reported crypto thefts this year. According to Chainalysis, the rogue state has stolen a total of $6.75 billion in cryptocurrency since records began — at least in known value.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/cryptocurrency/north-korean-hackers-steal-a-record-usd2-billion-in-crypto-in-2025-including-single-heist-worth-usd1-5-billion-report-claims-rogue-state-accounts-for-60-percent-of-all-reported-crypto-thefts-this-year-usd6-75-billion-total-since-records-began</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The perfect shot</title>
      <link>https://engineering.cmu.edu/news-events/news/2025/12/19-perfect-shot.html</link>
      <description>Carnegie Mellon University: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;researchers at Carnegie Mellon University have developed a new kind of lens that can bring an entire scene into sharp focus at once—no matter how far away or close different parts of the scene are.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.cmu.edu/news-events/news/2025/12/19-perfect-shot.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backing up Spotify</title>
      <link>https://annas-archive.li/blog/backing-up-spotify.html</link>
      <description>Anna&amp;#8217;s Archive: &amp;#8220;Anna’s Archive normally focuses on text (e.g. books and papers). We explained in &amp;#8216;The critical window of shadow libraries&amp;#8217; that we do this because text has the highest information density. But our mission (preserving humanity’s knowledge and culture) doesn’t distinguish among media types. Sometimes an opportunity comes along outside of text. This is such a case. A while ago, we discovered a way to scrape Spotify at scale. We saw a role for us here to build a music archive primarily aimed at preservation.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annas-archive.li/blog/backing-up-spotify.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Shutdown, WisconsinEye Discussing Future With Legislators</title>
      <link>https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2025/12/18/after-shutdown-wisconsineye-discussing-future-with-legislators/</link>
      <description>Urban Milwaukee: &amp;#8220;Due to a lack of funding, WisconsinEye halted its livestream coverage of state government on Monday and pulled down its video archive of over 30,000 hours of state government proceedings, candidate interviews and other programming. WisconsinEye launched in 2007 as an independent, nonprofit organization funded mostly by charitable donations.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2025/12/18/after-shutdown-wisconsineye-discussing-future-with-legislators/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developers can now submit apps to ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/developers-can-now-submit-apps-to-chatgpt/</link>
      <description>OpenAI: &amp;#8220;Earlier this year at DevDay, we introduced apps in ChatGPT. Starting today, developers can submit apps for review and publication in ChatGPT by following our app submission guidelines⁠(opens in a new window). Apps extend ChatGPT conversations by bringing in new context and letting users take actions like order groceries, turn an outline into a slide deck, or search for an apartment.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://openai.com/index/developers-can-now-submit-apps-to-chatgpt/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driverless Waymo seemingly drives straight into oncoming traffic in viral video</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/waymo-robotaxi-footage-wrong-side-of-road-viral-video</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;A recent viral video shows a driverless Waymo robotaxi driving straight into oncoming traffic in Austin, Texas. The post has garnered lots of upvotes on Reddit. In the video, you see that the robotaxi crawls to a halt facing the wrong direction, staring down oncoming traffic. Obviously out of sorts, it has its right turn signal on before whipping left into a gas station.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/waymo-robotaxi-footage-wrong-side-of-road-viral-video</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sydney Uni data goes walkabout after criminals raid code repo</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/19/sydney_uni_breach/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;The University of Sydney is ringing around thousands of current and former staff and students after admitting attackers helped themselves to historical personal data stashed inside one of its online code repositories.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/19/sydney_uni_breach/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DMCA “Bot War”: Google Search Processed 5 Billion Takedown Requests in 2025</title>
      <link>https://torrentfreak.com/a-dmca-bot-war-google-search-processed-5-billion-takedown-requests-in-2025/</link>
      <description>TorrentFreak: &amp;#8220;Google Search has reached a staggering new DMCA takedown milestone, processing over five billion copyright removal requests in 2025. Driven by a massive automated reporting spike, mostly from Link-Busters, the total all-time count has now eclipsed 15.8 billion.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://torrentfreak.com/a-dmca-bot-war-google-search-processed-5-billion-takedown-requests-in-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Court dismisses lawsuit over Disney&amp;#8217;s recreation of Peter Cushing in Rogue One</title>
      <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/110666-court-dismisses-lawsuit-over-disney-recreation-peter-cushing.html</link>
      <description>TechSpot: &amp;#8220;The strange legal fight between Disney and a 1970s horror movie production company over the CGI recreation of Peter Cushing in 2016&amp;#8217;s Rogue One: A Star Wars Story has ended. Unsurprisingly, the lawsuit has been thrown out after a judge found in favor of Disney and dismissed the claim.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techspot.com/news/110666-court-dismisses-lawsuit-over-disney-recreation-peter-cushing.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluvial Fingerprints: Major New Database Tracks Sediment Across Mississippi River Basin</title>
      <link>https://www.usu.edu/today/story/fluvial-fingerprints-major-new-database-tracks-sediment-across-mississippi-river-basin</link>
      <description>Utah State University: &amp;#8220;Tracking the sources of excessive sediment in the Mississippi River Basin (MRB) has proven to be a vexing and economically important question for the last few decades &amp;#8230; Now, the first basin-wide sediment fingerprinting database makes it possible to track where sediment is coming from and how it moves through the entire basin, allowing managers and researchers to better understand water quality, measure the health of waterways, minimize erosion and identify sources of pollution.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.usu.edu/today/story/fluvial-fingerprints-major-new-database-tracks-sediment-across-mississippi-river-basin</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google finds AI chatbots are only 69% accurate… at best</title>
      <link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/technology/google-finds-ai-chatbots-are-only-69-accurate-at-best/ar-AA1SCwzr</link>
      <description>Digital Trends: &amp;#8220;Using its newly introduced FACTS Benchmark Suite, the company found that even the best AI models struggle to break past a 70% factual accuracy rate. The top performer, Gemini 3 Pro, reached 69% overall accuracy, while other leading systems from OpenAI, Anthropic, and xAI scored even lower.&amp;#8221; We&amp;#8217;re destroying our water supplies and yeeting electricity prices for 69% accuracy AT BEST??!!!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/technology/google-finds-ai-chatbots-are-only-69-accurate-at-best/ar-AA1SCwzr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You can now play GTA Vice City directly in your web browser — no downloads, no installs, just instant nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/you-can-now-play-gta-vice-city-directly-in-your-web-browser-no-downloads-no-installs-just-instant-nostalgia</link>
      <description>Windows Central: &amp;#8220;A browser based demo lets you play GTA Vice City across multiple devices, highlighting just how far web technology and game preservation have come.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/you-can-now-play-gta-vice-city-directly-in-your-web-browser-no-downloads-no-installs-just-instant-nostalgia</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO launches the WHO Traditional Medicine Global Library</title>
      <link>https://www.paho.org/en/news/19-12-2025-who-launches-who-traditional-medicine-global-library</link>
      <description>Pan American Health Organization: &amp;#8220;The WHO Traditional Medicine Global Library is an inclusive and specialized digital information resource developed in collaboration with WHO Member States, civil society organizations, professional networks, academic institutions and initiatives across all WHO Regions. Its architecture comprises a global portal, six regional portals corresponding to the WHO Regions, and country-specific pages for 194 countries, enabling access to information according to national, regional and thematic contexts.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.paho.org/en/news/19-12-2025-who-launches-who-traditional-medicine-global-library</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The TikTok Awards were messy. I was there.</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/tiktok-awards-were-messy</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;TikTok brought the TikTok Awards to the U.S. for the first time this year — and after attending the underwhelming show in person, I&amp;#8217;m not totally convinced it should happen again. The night was a total disaster: full of tech mishaps, hot mics, and an ever-growing absent crowd.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/tiktok-awards-were-messy</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube hid the dislike button. Now it’s considering a name change.</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/19/youtube-dislike-button-hidden-not-interested/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;Some users in the experimental group will see the &amp;#8216;Dislike&amp;#8217; title, while others will see &amp;#8216;Not Interested.&amp;#8217; YouTube’s goal, as stated in the Support thread, is to determine whether users use those terms &amp;#8216;interchangeably.&apos;&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/19/youtube-dislike-button-hidden-not-interested/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Will Ship with an “AI Kill Switch” to Completely Disable all AI Features</title>
      <link>https://9to5linux.com/firefox-will-ship-with-an-ai-kill-switch-to-completely-disable-all-ai-features</link>
      <description>9to5 Linux: &amp;#8220;After the controversial news shared earlier this week by Mozilla’s new CEO that Firefox will evolve into &amp;#8216;a modern AI browser,&amp;#8217; the company now revealed it is working on an AI kill switch for the open-source web browser.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://9to5linux.com/firefox-will-ship-with-an-ai-kill-switch-to-completely-disable-all-ai-features</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At least 16 files have disappeared from the DOJ webpage for documents related to Jeffrey Epstein</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/release-epstein-files-justice-department-trump-9290fcaad1cb6fcb1cbc1befabc01994?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=6947157a12b0720001eb74da&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+New+Content+%28Feed%29&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;At least 16 files disappeared from the Justice Department’s public webpage for documents related to Jeffrey Epstein — including a photograph showing President Donald Trump — less than a day after they were posted, with no explanation from the government and no notice to the public.&amp;#8221; Legal expert Anne P. Mitchell is grabbing the files as they are released and writing about it. You can find her Substack at https://substack.com/@annepmitchell.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/release-epstein-files-justice-department-trump-9290fcaad1cb6fcb1cbc1befabc01994?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=6947157a12b0720001eb74da&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+New+Content+%28Feed%29&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking News: AI runs vending machine, immediately invents Snack Communism</title>
      <link>https://www.geeksaresexy.net/2025/12/19/breaking-news-ai-runs-vending-machine-immediately-invents-snack-communism/</link>
      <description>Geeks Are Sexy: &amp;#8220;The Wall Street Journal let an AI named Claudius run a vending machine as a &amp;#8216;real-world stress test.&amp;#8217; It started with $1,000, full autonomy, and one very basic mission: sell snacks, make money, don’t collapse society. Within days, Claudius had lost more than its entire budget, declared an Ultra-Capitalist Free-For-All, gave everything away for free, bought a PlayStation 5 &amp;#8216;for marketing,&amp;#8217; and ordered a live fish to boost employee morale.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.geeksaresexy.net/2025/12/19/breaking-news-ai-runs-vending-machine-immediately-invents-snack-communism/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI&amp;#8217;s Stargate data center gets approval to receive 1.4 gigawatts of power in Michigan — some residents furious as energy company is given go-ahead by regulatory body without hearing opposition</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/openais-stargate-data-center-gets-approval-to-receive-1-4-gigawatts-of-power-in-michigan-some-residents-furious-as-energy-company-is-given-go-ahead-by-regulatory-body-without-hearing-opposition</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;This move meant that DTE Energy did not have to go through a lengthy hearing, wherein opposing groups could seek expert testimony and present evidence to challenge DTE’s claims. Many residents are concerned that this massive project would cause electricity prices to spike and affect the water quality in the area — issues that several U.S. senators are also looking into.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/openais-stargate-data-center-gets-approval-to-receive-1-4-gigawatts-of-power-in-michigan-some-residents-furious-as-energy-company-is-given-go-ahead-by-regulatory-body-without-hearing-opposition</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a Reddit tipster cracked the Brown University and MIT shooting cases</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/reddit-tipster-cracked-brown-university-mit-shooting-cases-rcna250036</link>
      <description>NBC News: &amp;#8220;Having unleashed a multiagency manhunt — involving the Providence police, the FBI and a $50,000 reward — the clue investigators needed in the Brown University shooting was ultimately found not on a street corner but in a Reddit thread.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/reddit-tipster-cracked-brown-university-mit-shooting-cases-rcna250036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A black hole’: families and police say tech giants delay investigations in child abuse and drug cases</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/dec/19/meta-snapchat-tech-giant-child-abuse-drug-cases</link>
      <description>The Guardian: &amp;#8220;The Guardian has reviewed four cases where Snap Inc and Meta have delayed or declined to comply with warrants and subpoenas requesting information related to serious crimes linked to their platforms.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/dec/19/meta-snapchat-tech-giant-child-abuse-drug-cases</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instacart to Pay $60 Million in Refunds for Allegedly Deceiving Customers</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/instacart-to-pay-60-million-in-refunds-for-allegedly-deceiving-customers-2000701915</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;Instacart’s month keeps getting worse. The grocery delivery service was hit with another blow on Thursday, when the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) announced the company agreed to issue $60 million in refunds to settle allegations that it engaged in deceptive business practices.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/instacart-to-pay-60-million-in-refunds-for-allegedly-deceiving-customers-2000701915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biodegradable technology can dissolve into harmful microplastics, Northeastern research uncovers</title>
      <link>https://news.northeastern.edu/2025/12/19/degradability-transient-electronics-research/</link>
      <description>Northeastern University: &amp;#8220;Northeastern University researchers have discovered that materials used in the development of transient electronics — devices designed to biodegrade at the end of their life — can break down into microplastics, casting doubt on the true dissolvability of these devices over time.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.northeastern.edu/2025/12/19/degradability-transient-electronics-research/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We asked four AI coding agents to rebuild Minesweeper—the results were explosive</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/12/the-ars-technica-ai-coding-agent-test-minesweeper-edition/</link>
      <description>Ars Technica: &amp;#8220;To see how effective these modern AI coding tools are becoming, we decided to test four major models with a simple task: re-creating the classic Windows game Minesweeper. Since it’s relatively easy for pattern-matching systems like LLMs to play off of existing code to re-create famous games, we added in one novelty curveball as well.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/12/the-ars-technica-ai-coding-agent-test-minesweeper-edition/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Climate Policy Database maps mitigation policies across the 60 IFCMA countries</title>
      <link>https://www.oecd.org/en/about/news/press-releases/2025/12/new-climate-policy-database-maps-mitigation-policies-across-60-countries.html?utm_source=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_medium=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_campaign=news</link>
      <description>OECD: &amp;#8220;The Inclusive Forum on Carbon Mitigation Approaches (IFCMA) has released the first edition of its Climate Policy Database, providing unprecedented detail on how governments are tackling climate change through policy action.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.oecd.org/en/about/news/press-releases/2025/12/new-climate-policy-database-maps-mitigation-policies-across-60-countries.html?utm_source=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_medium=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_campaign=news</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HKBU opens free online Chinese medicine diet database for everyday wellness</title>
      <link>https://www.thestandard.com.hk/hong-kong-news/article/319532/HKBU-opens-free-online-Chinese-medicine-diet-database-for-everyday-wellness</link>
      <description>The Standard (Hong Kong): &amp;#8220;Hong Kong Baptist University (HKBU) has launched a free online Chinese Medicine Diet and Health Images Database &amp;#8230; The database, developed by a research team led by Professor Chen Hubiao from HKBU’s School of Chinese Medicine, features 124 carefully curated recipes designed to support daily health through diet.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thestandard.com.hk/hong-kong-news/article/319532/HKBU-opens-free-online-Chinese-medicine-diet-database-for-everyday-wellness</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What have San Francisco police been doing at 16th and Mission?</title>
      <link>https://missionlocal.org/2025/12/sf-16th-street-mission-daily-crime/</link>
      <description>Mission Local: &amp;#8220;It’s been nearly 300 days since Mayor Daniel Lurie announced a plan to clean up the 16th Street BART Plaza. To mark the occasion, Mission Local is adding a new tool for tracking his promises: A dashboard, updated daily, that notes the arrests and citations issued by San Francisco police officers in a 300-meter radius around 16th and Mission streets.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://missionlocal.org/2025/12/sf-16th-street-mission-daily-crime/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘It’s hardly imaginable that the VDB can survive’</title>
      <link>https://chicagoreader.com/film-tv/movie-feature/video-data-bank-saic-layoffs/</link>
      <description>Chicago Reader: &amp;#8220;The news comes at a time when arts organizations nationwide are under siege, particularly those on the margins of the margins, so to speak; fields like video art are often misunderstood at best and spurned at worst. It has been daunting for those involved, both directly affected and otherwise.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chicagoreader.com/film-tv/movie-feature/video-data-bank-saic-layoffs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Flickr Archives with Data Lifeboat</title>
      <link>https://blog.flickr.net/en/2025/12/16/building-flickr-archives-with-data-lifeboat/</link>
      <description>Flickr Blog: &amp;#8220;With Data Lifeboat, you can create an archive to document a specific time and place, share memories of an event, or curate a collection of perspectives from around the globe. Simply put, conscious archiving with Data Lifeboat can allow you to create and share your own slice of history with future viewers from this vast collection. Here are some Data Lifeboat examples from activity so far…&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.flickr.net/en/2025/12/16/building-flickr-archives-with-data-lifeboat/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Tool Can Tell You If Your Home Network Has Been Compromised</title>
      <link>https://lifehacker.com/tech/tool-checks-for-compromised-home-internet?utm_medium=RSS</link>
      <description>Lifehacker: &amp;#8220;IP Check, from threat monitoring firm GreyNoise, will alert you if your IP address has been observed scanning the internet as part of a botnet or residential proxy network.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lifehacker.com/tech/tool-checks-for-compromised-home-internet?utm_medium=RSS</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-generated images of Bondi gunman used to spread false information</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/verify-disinformation-and-deepfakes-after-bondi-attack/106154250</link>
      <description>ABC News (Australia): &amp;#8220;Falsehoods and conspiracy theories are spreading online following the horrific Bondi Beach attack. ABC NEWS Verify has analysed three instances where AI-generated images, or in one case a real image taken out of context, are attempting to twist the narrative on social media.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/verify-disinformation-and-deepfakes-after-bondi-attack/106154250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ninth Circuit lets X pursue international defamation cases against Media Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/ninth-circuit-lets-x-pursue-international-defamation-cases-against-media-matters/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;Elon Musk’s X can proceed with international litigation against media watchdog Media Matters after a Ninth Circuit panel reversed an anti-suit injunction issued by a lower court.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/ninth-circuit-lets-x-pursue-international-defamation-cases-against-media-matters/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biologists at IU create insect DNA database to aid environmental, agricultural research</title>
      <link>https://news.iu.edu/live/news/48219-biologists-at-iu-create-insect-dna-database-to-aid-env?utm_source=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_medium=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_campaign=news</link>
      <description>Indiana University: &amp;#8220;Is there such a thing as a better bug? Researchers at Indiana University are pioneering an insect DNA database to find out. Built to empower researchers, the database will accelerate the discovery of insect-based solutions to solve environmental and agriculture problems.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.iu.edu/live/news/48219-biologists-at-iu-create-insect-dna-database-to-aid-env?utm_source=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_medium=miragenews&amp;#038;utm_campaign=news</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slop, vibe coding and glazing: AI dominates 2025’s words of the year</title>
      <link>https://theconversation.com/slop-vibe-coding-and-glazing-ai-dominates-2025s-words-of-the-year-269688</link>
      <description>The Conversation: &amp;#8220;The words of the year aren’t just a fun peek into new slang and language changes, they also tell us quite a bit about the worries, trends and obsessions of the English-speaking world. And this year’s list has one clear theme. In 2025, artificial intelligence (AI) played a huge role in our offices, social media feeds, music and film, and now – dictionaries.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theconversation.com/slop-vibe-coding-and-glazing-ai-dominates-2025s-words-of-the-year-269688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How The New Yorker digitized its entire magazine archive</title>
      <link>https://www.fastcompany.com/91462859/how-the-new-yorker-digitized-its-entire-magazine-archive?partner=rss</link>
      <description>Fast Company: &amp;#8220;You can now read every article that has ever appeared in The New Yorker—from as early as February 1925—with the click of a button&amp;#8230; the content has also been incorporated into The New Yorker’s search algorithm so that readers can come across it organically.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.fastcompany.com/91462859/how-the-new-yorker-digitized-its-entire-magazine-archive?partner=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ProPublica’s New Tool Provides Drug Info the FDA Won’t</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/propublicas-new-tool-provides-drug-info-the-fda-wont-2000701357</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;Today, ProPublica is launching Rx Inspector, a first-of-its-kind database that provides answers to what the FDA won’t tell us: where our generics are coming from and the track records of the factories that made them. The information is harder to find than you may think.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/propublicas-new-tool-provides-drug-info-the-fda-wont-2000701357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Decides That Google Assistant Can Stick Around a Bit Longer, Pushes Gemini Switch to 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.droid-life.com/2025/12/19/google-assistant-switch-to-gemini-delay/</link>
      <description>Droid Life: &amp;#8220;You may have forgotten the timeline, but Google was pushing to force all off of Google Assistant and onto Gemini by the end of this year. Like with all things AI, the timing hasn’t quite worked out and they are instead &amp;#8216;adjusting&amp;#8217; that previous timeline to a later date within 2026.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.droid-life.com/2025/12/19/google-assistant-switch-to-gemini-delay/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As EPA moves to fast-track data centers, some cities are moving to slow them down</title>
      <link>https://www.constructiondive.com/news/epa-fast-track-data-centers-cities-push-back/808245/</link>
      <description>Construction Dive: &amp;#8220;In their letter to Congress, the environmental organizations stated that tripling the number of data centers in the next five years would require as much electricity as about 30 million households, as much water as about 18.5 million households and contribute to escalating electricity costs.  Bloomberg reported in September that wholesale power costs as much as 267% more than it did five years ago in areas near data centers.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.constructiondive.com/news/epa-fast-track-data-centers-cities-push-back/808245/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Shuts Down Channels Using AI To Create Fake Movie Trailers Watched By Millions</title>
      <link>https://deadline.com/2025/12/youtube-terminates-screen-culture-kh-studio-fake-ai-trailer-1236652506/</link>
      <description>Deadline: &amp;#8220;The Google-owned video giant has switched off Screen Culture and KH Studio, which together boasted well over 2 million subscribers and more than a billion views.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deadline.com/2025/12/youtube-terminates-screen-culture-kh-studio-fake-ai-trailer-1236652506/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google warns staff with US visas against international travel due to embassy delays</title>
      <link>https://www.thestandard.com.hk/world-news/article/319795/Google-warns-staff-with-US-visas-against-international-travel-due-to-embassy-delays</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;Alphabet&amp;#8217;s Google has advised some employees on U.S. visas to avoid international travel due to delays at embassies, Business Insider reported on Friday, citing an internal email.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thestandard.com.hk/world-news/article/319795/Google-warns-staff-with-US-visas-against-international-travel-due-to-embassy-delays</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministries collaborate to digitize national cultural heritage</title>
      <link>https://en.antaranews.com/news/397078/ministries-collaborate-to-digitize-national-cultural-heritage</link>
      <description>Antara News: &amp;#8220;The Ministry of Communication and Digital (Kemkomdigi) and the Ministry of Culture (Kemenbud) are collaborating to digitize national cultural heritage. This initiative aims to provide broad, structured, and sustainable public access to Indonesian cultural data.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://en.antaranews.com/news/397078/ministries-collaborate-to-digitize-national-cultural-heritage</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian WhatsApp tutors are teaching ordinary people how to use AI</title>
      <link>https://restofworld.org/2025/indian-tutors-ai-skills/</link>
      <description>Rest of World: &amp;#8220;Every evening, Keshev Dutt spends a couple of hours in his home in northern India, teaching small business owners in Bangladesh and Nepal how to use artificial intelligence. Not for coding or building chatbots, but for something more basic: AI in Excel. For $30 per head for a three-month program, Dutt, 28, runs classes in WhatsApp and Facebook groups, as well as on Zoom.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://restofworld.org/2025/indian-tutors-ai-skills/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Sued SerpApi Over Scraping Search Results</title>
      <link>https://www.seroundtable.com/google-sues-serpapi-40631.html</link>
      <description>Search Engine Roundtable: &amp;#8220;On Friday, Google announced it had filed a lawsuit (PDF) against SerpApi for scraping the Google search results. Google alleges that SerpApi is running an &amp;#8216;unlawful&amp;#8217; operation that bypasses Google’s security measures to scrape search results at an astonishing scale.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.seroundtable.com/google-sues-serpapi-40631.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark accuses Russia of supporting cyberattacks on water, elections</title>
      <link>https://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2025/12/19/denmark-russia-cyberattack-water-elections/2101766168463/</link>
      <description>UPI: &amp;#8220;The Danish Defense Intelligence Service said it determined that Russia was behind a cyberattack on a Danish water utility in 2024 and a series of distributed denial-of-service attacks on Danish websites before the 2025 municipal and regional council elections in the country, the agency said in a press release.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2025/12/19/denmark-russia-cyberattack-water-elections/2101766168463/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How misreading Google Trends is fuelling Bondi attack conspiracy theories</title>
      <link>https://theconversation.com/how-misreading-google-trends-is-fuelling-bondi-attack-conspiracy-theories-272251</link>
      <description>The Conversation: &amp;#8220;Google told the ABC Google Trends may sometimes show searches when none actually happened due to &amp;#8216;statistical noise&amp;#8217;. I have studied the mechanics of Google Trends extensively in my research, and I can confirm this is true – and the &amp;#8216;noise&amp;#8217; can lead to strange results, especially when looking at searches for unusual terms or coming from small areas.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theconversation.com/how-misreading-google-trends-is-fuelling-bondi-attack-conspiracy-theories-272251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X payments incentivised misinformation in wake of Bondi shooting, expert says</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/expert-says-x-incentivising-misinformation-bondi-shooting/106152144</link>
      <description>ABC News (Australia): &amp;#8220;Disinformation expert Timothy Graham says X&amp;#8217;s content monetisation program is providing an incentive for users to share misinformation. X and other social media platforms were flooded with false and misleading claims following the attack on Bondi Beach.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/expert-says-x-incentivising-misinformation-bondi-shooting/106152144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>