<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ResearchBuzz - Transformed</title>
    <link>https://researchbuzz.me</link>
    <description>News and resources covering social media, search engines, databases, archives, and other such information collections. Since 1998.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:39:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Shofo</title>
      <link>https://shofo.ai/</link>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been following this company for a while and it&amp;#8217;s finally launched: From the front page: &amp;#8220;Complete Social Media Data Indexes. Query 100M+ videos with SQL. Every field. Real-time.&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s a collection of several APIs for getting social media data from LinkedIn, Twitter, TikTok, and Instagram. I&amp;#8217;m planning to spend some time with this one after the first of the year.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shofo.ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Sega Channel Games Saved In Latest VGHF Project</title>
      <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-sega-channel-games-saved-in-latest-vghf-project/1100-6536975/</link>
      <description>GameSpot: &amp;#8220;Sega Channel launched in 1994 and was one of the first subscription-based, digital game services, beaming new games and content directly to players&amp;#8217; consoles through a television cable. The service shut down in 1998, and since then many of the exclusive games and content available on the service were thought to be gone forever. That is, until the Video Game History Foundation embarked on a quest to see the channel&amp;#8217;s unique history, and its content, preserved.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-sega-channel-games-saved-in-latest-vghf-project/1100-6536975/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merriam-Webster’s 2025 word of the year is ‘slop’</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/merriam-webster-dictionary-word-year-2025-slop-2dffb2379cac6001aa30e148669e3393?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=69401482fbf4d40001af32e8&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;Creepy, zany and demonstrably fake content is often called &amp;#8216;slop.&amp;#8217; The word’s proliferation online, in part thanks to the widespread availability of generative artificial intelligence, landed it Merriam-Webster’s 2025 word of the year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/merriam-webster-dictionary-word-year-2025-slop-2dffb2379cac6001aa30e148669e3393?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=69401482fbf4d40001af32e8&amp;#038;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=social&amp;#038;utm_source=bluesky</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yandex Updates Maps to Reduce Navigation Errors Amid GPS Disruptions</title>
      <link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/12/15/yandex-updates-maps-to-reduce-navigation-errors-amid-gps-disruptions-a91440</link>
      <description>Moscow Times: &amp;#8220;Disruptions to satellite navigation have become increasingly common in Russia as the military deploys anti-drone systems to counter Ukrainian attacks that rely on GPS guidance. Those measures have included signal jamming and spoofing, particularly near sensitive locations such as the Kremlin, causing widespread problems for civilian navigation.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/12/15/yandex-updates-maps-to-reduce-navigation-errors-amid-gps-disruptions-a91440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Militant groups are experimenting with AI, and the risks are expected to grow</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/militant-groups-are-experimenting-with-ai-and-the-risks-are-expected-to-grow</link>
      <description>PBS: &amp;#8220;For extremist organizations, AI could be a powerful tool for recruiting new members, churning out realistic deepfake images and refining their cyberattacks, national security experts and spy agencies have warned.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/militant-groups-are-experimenting-with-ai-and-the-risks-are-expected-to-grow</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LG TV users baffled by unremovable Microsoft Copilot installation — surprise forced update shows app pinned to the home screen</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/service-providers/tv-providers/lg-tv-update-adds-non-removable-microsoft-copilot-app-to-webos</link>
      <description>Tom&amp;#8217;s Hardware: &amp;#8220;LG smart TV owners are reporting that a recent webOS software update has added Microsoft Copilot to their TVs, with no apparent way to remove it. Reports first surfaced over the weekend on Reddit, where a post showing a Copilot tile pinned to an LG TV home screen climbed to more than 35,000 upvotes on r/mildlyinfuriating, accompanied by hundreds of comments from users describing the same behavior.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tomshardware.com/service-providers/tv-providers/lg-tv-update-adds-non-removable-microsoft-copilot-app-to-webos</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5.2 vs Gemini 3 — How the two heavyweight models compare on benchmarks, price, and feature set</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/openai-gpt-5-2-vs-google-gemini-3-how-they-compare</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;So, how does OpenAI&amp;#8217;s GPT-5.2 stack up against Google&amp;#8217;s Gemini 3? So far, the models seem evenly matched on benchmark performance, pricing, and other comparisons, with both models gaining an edge in specific areas.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/openai-gpt-5-2-vs-google-gemini-3-how-they-compare</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US social media requirements for foreign visitors could have &amp;#8216;chilling effect&amp;#8217; on travel, industry group says</title>
      <link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/us-social-media-requirements-for-foreign-visitors-could-have-chilling-effect-on-travel-industry-group-says/ar-AA1So7Qj</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;A group representing the U.S. travel and tourism industry warned Monday that a proposal to require millions of foreign visitors to provide social media handles used over the past five years could have a &amp;#8216;chilling effect&amp;#8217; on visits to the United States.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/us/us-social-media-requirements-for-foreign-visitors-could-have-chilling-effect-on-travel-industry-group-says/ar-AA1So7Qj</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who wanted $75 million for Lambo.com domain is forced to hand it over to Lamborghini</title>
      <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/110546-man-who-wanted-75-million-lambocom-domain-forced.html</link>
      <description>TechSpot: &amp;#8220;There have been plenty of instances over the decades of people making small fortunes by selling domain names, but the practice isn&amp;#8217;t risk free. A man who bought Lambo.com hoped to get $75 million for the name. Unfortunately, a court made him turn it over to Lamborghini for nothing.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techspot.com/news/110546-man-who-wanted-75-million-lambocom-domain-forced.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Florida AG sues Roblox over child safety concerns</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/florida-ag-sues-roblox-over-child-safety-concerns/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;Florida Attorney General James Uthmeier took aim at the Roblox Corporation on Thursday in a lawsuit calling the online game platform a &amp;#8216;hunting ground for sexual predators.&amp;#8217; In the 76-page complaint, Uthmeier outlined insufficient age verification controls to prevent children from accessing adult content while also allowing adults to contact minors.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/florida-ag-sues-roblox-over-child-safety-concerns/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI superintelligence is a Silicon Valley fantasy, Ai2 researcher says</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/ai_superintelligence_fantasy/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;You want artificial general intelligence (AGI)? Current-day processors aren&amp;#8217;t powerful enough to make it happen and our ability to scale up may soon be coming to an end, argues well-known researcher Tim Dettmers.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/ai_superintelligence_fantasy/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searchable Bronze Age site database could help answer key questions about ancient Anatolia</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-12-searchable-bronze-age-site-database.html</link>
      <description>Phys.org: &amp;#8220;To boost our understanding of a little-known civilization that thrived more than 3,000 years ago, scientists have built an easy-to-use digital catalog of 483 Bronze Age sites in western Anatolia.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phys.org/news/2025-12-searchable-bronze-age-site-database.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Takes Down Disney AI Videos Following Cease &amp;#038; Desist</title>
      <link>https://deadline.com/2025/12/google-takes-down-disney-ai-videos-cease-desist-1236647823/</link>
      <description>Deadline: &amp;#8220;Google is cooperating with Disney‘s cease and desist, removing dozens of AI-generated videos featuring characters belonging to the century-old entertainment conglomerate. Following the Disney’s $1B deal with OpenAI for three-year licensing of several characters on Sora, Google has taken down dozens of AI videos from YouTube featuring Mickey Mouse, Deadpool, Moana and more.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deadline.com/2025/12/google-takes-down-disney-ai-videos-cease-desist-1236647823/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center for Counteracting Disinformation: Russia rapidly expands its information and intelligence influence in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://odessa-journal.com/center-for-counteracting-disinformation-russia-rapidly-expands-its-information-and-intelligence-influence-in-mexico</link>
      <description>Odessa Journal: &amp;#8220;After the start of Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, Russian propaganda channels RT and Sputnik have significantly expanded their presence in Mexico, spreading anti-American and anti-Ukrainian narratives, according to the Center for Countering Disinformation of the National Security and Defense Council of Ukraine.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://odessa-journal.com/center-for-counteracting-disinformation-russia-rapidly-expands-its-information-and-intelligence-influence-in-mexico</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk teams with El Salvador to bring Grok chatbot to public schools</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/dec/11/elon-musk-el-salvador-grok</link>
      <description>The Guardian: &amp;#8220;Elon Musk is partnering with the government of El Salvador to bring his artificial intelligence company’s chatbot, Grok, to more than 1 million students across the country, according to a Thursday announcement by xAI. Over the next two years, the plan is to &amp;#8216;deploy&amp;#8217; the chatbot to more than 5,000 public schools in an &amp;#8216;AI-powered education program&amp;#8217;.&amp;#8221; yikes.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/dec/11/elon-musk-el-salvador-grok</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers tricked ChatGPT, Grok and Google into helping them install malware</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/cybersecurity/hackers-tricked-chatgpt-grok-and-google-into-helping-them-install-malware-185711492.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230; hackers are apparently using AI prompts to seed Google search results with dangerous commands. When executed by unknowing users, these commands prompt computers to give the hackers the access they need to install malware.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/cybersecurity/hackers-tricked-chatgpt-grok-and-google-into-helping-them-install-malware-185711492.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyberattack Reportedly Paralyzes Russia’s Military Registration Database</title>
      <link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/12/11/cyberattack-paralyzes-russias-military-registration-database-a91410</link>
      <description>The Moscow Times: &amp;#8220;Anonymous hackers have breached a key developer of Russia’s digital military draft system, the head of the draft-dodging nonprofit Idite Lesom said Thursday&amp;#8230;. [Grigory] Sverdlin said his group received a large set of documents from the hackers, including the source code, technical documentation and internal communications from the developer, Russia’s software and digital solutions provider Micord.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/12/11/cyberattack-paralyzes-russias-military-registration-database-a91410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judge’s Footnote on Immigration Agents Using AI in Chicago Area Raises Accuracy and Privacy Concerns</title>
      <link>https://news.wttw.com/2025/11/26/judge-s-footnote-immigration-agents-using-ai-chicago-area-raises-accuracy-and-privacy</link>
      <description>WTTW: &amp;#8220;Tucked in a two-sentence footnote in a voluminous court opinion, a federal judge recently called out immigration agents using artificial intelligence to write use-of-force reports, raising concerns that it could lead to inaccuracies and further erode public confidence in how police have handled the immigration crackdown in the Chicago area and ensuing protests.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.wttw.com/2025/11/26/judge-s-footnote-immigration-agents-using-ai-chicago-area-raises-accuracy-and-privacy</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hard problems in social media archiving</title>
      <link>https://alexwlchan.net/2025/hard-problems-in-social-media-archiving/?ref=rss</link>
      <description>Alex Chan: &amp;#8220;Institutional archiving has different constraints to individual collections – institutions serve a much wider audience, so their decisions need consistency and boundaries. My own scrapbook is tiny and personal, and comparing it alongside institutional efforts really highlights the differences and difficulties. It’s why I usually call it a &amp;#8216;scrapbook&amp;#8217;, not an &amp;#8216;archive&amp;#8217;: it’s informal and a bit chaotic, and that’s fine because it’s only for me. In this post, I’ll explain what I see as the key issues facing institutional social media archiving: what can be saved, what resists preservation, and how context is so hard to keep.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexwlchan.net/2025/hard-problems-in-social-media-archiving/?ref=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK-US research project launched to study the relationship between Wikipedia and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://news.exeter.ac.uk/faculty-of-humanities-arts-and-social-sciences/uk-us-research-project-launched-to-study-the-relationship-between-wikipedia-and-generative-ai/</link>
      <description>University of Exeter: &amp;#8220;Experts in Artificial Intelligence are to collaborate on a transatlantic research project looking at the relationship between Wikipedia and generative AI. Curating the Commons – AI, Wikipedia, and the Reconstruction of Notability will explore how the globally renowned repository of information both shapes, and is shaped by, the rise of AI and large language models (LLMs).&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.exeter.ac.uk/faculty-of-humanities-arts-and-social-sciences/uk-us-research-project-launched-to-study-the-relationship-between-wikipedia-and-generative-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When people see themselves in science, they trust it more</title>
      <link>https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/demographic-representation-public-trust-science-688912/</link>
      <description>University of Rochester: &amp;#8220;White men make up about two-thirds of the scientific workforce in the United States, and nearly all scientists—92 percent—are from non-rural areas, according to the study. That the scientific community looks a lot less like the country it serves is more than symbolic, the authors argue. Indeed, it influences how different groups of people trust scientists and scientific institutions, and how likely recommendations of scientists are to become public policy.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/demographic-representation-public-trust-science-688912/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avalanche Canada launches new database for fatal avalanche incidents</title>
      <link>https://ntv.ca/news/avalanche-canada-launches-new-database-for-fatal-avalanche-incidents/</link>
      <description>NTV: &amp;#8220;Avalanche Canada has just launched a new site documenting every known avalanche fatality in Canada since 1792. In addition to incident reports on these fatal incidents, the site also has expert incident analyses on most avalanches dating back to 1955, as well as interactive mapping, statistics and case studies.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ntv.ca/news/avalanche-canada-launches-new-database-for-fatal-avalanche-incidents/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Website Lets You Scan Snaps for Known Security Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2025/12/snapscope-snap-security-vulnerability-checker</link>
      <description>OMG Ubuntu: &amp;#8220;Ever wondered how secure the apps you install from the Snap Store are? A new website from Ubuntu alumnus Alan Pope makes it easy to find out. The Snapscope website uses open-source security tool Grype to scan Snap package for CVEs and security vulnerabilities (critical, high, medium, low, actively exploited) which might affect those using them.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2025/12/snapscope-snap-security-vulnerability-checker</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit challenges Australia&amp;#8217;s law banning children under 16 from social media</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/reddit-challenges-australias-world-law-banning-children-16-128330665</link>
      <description>ABC News: &amp;#8220;Global online forum Reddit on Friday filed a court challenge to Australia’s world-first law that bans Australian children younger than 16 from holding accounts on the world’s most popular social media platforms.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/reddit-challenges-australias-world-law-banning-children-16-128330665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit is starting to verify public figures</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/social-media/reddit-is-starting-to-verify-public-figures-170000833.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;Like it or not, the checkmark has become an almost universal symbol on most social platforms, even though its exact meaning can vary significantly between services. Now, Reddit, which historically hasn&amp;#8217;t cared that much about its users&amp;#8217; identity, is joining the club and starting to test verification for public figures on its platform.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/social-media/reddit-is-starting-to-verify-public-figures-170000833.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A popular video of a priest blocking ICE agents isn’t real</title>
      <link>https://www.poynter.org/fact-checking/2025/catholic-priest-blocks-ice-agents-church-video/</link>
      <description>Poynter: &amp;#8220;Social media videos of a Catholic priest turning away Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents from his church are garnering support and thousands of shares, but they were generated with artificial intelligence tools.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.poynter.org/fact-checking/2025/catholic-priest-blocks-ice-agents-church-video/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>xAI Answers the Question, ‘What if Product Placement was Significantly Worse?’</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/xai-answers-the-question-what-if-product-placement-was-significantly-worse-2000697957</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;The AI company owned by Elon Musk recently hosted a hackathon that invited people to build new features and functionality with the company’s AI models. One group of upstart engineers created Halftime, described as a tool that &amp;#8216;Dynamically weaves AI-generated ads into the scenes you’re watching, so breaks feel like part of the story instead of interruptions.&amp;#8217; It is, frankly, awful.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/xai-answers-the-question-what-if-product-placement-was-significantly-worse-2000697957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google to build subsea cables in Papua New Guinea under Australia defence treaty</title>
      <link>https://www.thestandard.com.hk/world-news/article/319235/Google-to-build-subsea-cables-in-Papua-New-Guinea-under-Australia-defence-treaty</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;Alphabet&amp;#8217;s Google will build three subsea cables in Papua New Guinea, which the largest Pacific Island nation said was funded by Australia under a mutual defence treaty, in a key upgrade to its digital backbone.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thestandard.com.hk/world-news/article/319235/Google-to-build-subsea-cables-in-Papua-New-Guinea-under-Australia-defence-treaty</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New PyStoreRAT Malware Targets OSINT Researchers Through GitHub</title>
      <link>https://hackread.com/pystorerat-rat-malware-github-osint-researchers/</link>
      <description>HackRead: &amp;#8220;These convincing projects/repositories were so well-made that several quickly climbed high on GitHub’s trending lists. Only after gaining this traction and trust did the criminals introduce subtle code updates, disguised as simple ‘maintenance, to plant the PyStoreRAT backdoor.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackread.com/pystorerat-rat-malware-github-osint-researchers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai army accuses Cambodia of endangering cultural heritage sites, escalating tensions in border dispute</title>
      <link>https://theindependent.sg/thai-army-accuses-cambodia-of-endangering-cultural-heritage-sites-escalating-tensions-in-border-dispute/</link>
      <description>The Independent (Singapore): &amp;#8220;The Thai army has issued a stark warning to Cambodia, urging the neighbouring country not to turn cultural heritage sites into military strongholds. Maj. Gen. Winthai Suvaree, spokesperson for the Royal Thai Army, stressed Thursday that such actions violate the 1954 Hague Convention, which protects historical sites during armed conflict.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theindependent.sg/thai-army-accuses-cambodia-of-endangering-cultural-heritage-sites-escalating-tensions-in-border-dispute/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banning under-16s from social media is a half-measure. We should ban toxic algorithms</title>
      <link>https://www.thejournal.ie/readme/opinion-social-media-ban-australia-go-further-recommender-systems-algorithm-6901718-Dec2025/</link>
      <description>The Journal (Ireland): &amp;#8220;We need to promote non-profit, decentralised alternatives such as the non-profit German social media network Mastodon, as well as other public, non-profit, and democratic alternatives which focus on building community, connecting people, and supporting culture and community, rather than maximising profit at all costs.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thejournal.ie/readme/opinion-social-media-ban-australia-go-further-recommender-systems-algorithm-6901718-Dec2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Should Start a Blog Now (or Later)</title>
      <link>https://chrisenns.com/2025/12/you-should-start-a-blog-now-or-later/</link>
      <description>Faraway, So Close: &amp;#8220;There are a hundred ways to type into your computer or phone and have them appear on the internet. I&amp;#8217;m going to recommend two right now, but either will work just fine. And thanks to fancy words like &amp;#8216;data portability&amp;#8217;, you can change to a different way of publishing words on the internet if you decide to later.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chrisenns.com/2025/12/you-should-start-a-blog-now-or-later/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&amp;#8217;m never getting any work done ever again, thanks to this website that lets me play thousands of user-made Doom levels in my browser</title>
      <link>https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/im-never-getting-any-work-done-ever-again-thanks-to-this-website-that-lets-me-play-thousands-of-user-made-doom-levels-in-my-browser/</link>
      <description>PC Gamer: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;an entire subculture of Doom modding has just been excavated in a way that might spell actual doom for my career. DoomScroll is a new website that lets users scroll through and play thousands (and I mean thousands) of user-made Doom WADs right in your browser.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/im-never-getting-any-work-done-ever-again-thanks-to-this-website-that-lets-me-play-thousands-of-user-made-doom-levels-in-my-browser/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I think I need to order more boxes. I&amp;#8217;m playing box-chicken with the stuff I have left to pack. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launching CivicMapper: Visualizing Land Values in 3D</title>
      <link>https://progressandpoverty.substack.com/p/launching-civicmapper-visualizing</link>
      <description>Progress and Poverty: &amp;#8220;Today, we are thrilled to launch CivicMapper, a new interactive tool that brings cities to life through 3D visualizations&amp;#8230;. CivicMapper lets you explore geospatial data as extruded 3D bars, each representing the land value or property characteristics of every parcel in a city.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://progressandpoverty.substack.com/p/launching-civicmapper-visualizing</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Care, Community, and UCSF History Now Digitized and Online</title>
      <link>https://www.library.ucsf.edu/news/stories-of-care-community-and-ucsf-history-now-digitized-and-online/</link>
      <description>UC San Francisco: &amp;#8220;These digital collections reflect rich histories that inform contemporary medical practices and the health sciences. They also provide a deeper understanding of the people who built UCSF and the communities it serves, as well as the artistry and activism embedded in care, and the lived experiences captured through journals and correspondence.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.library.ucsf.edu/news/stories-of-care-community-and-ucsf-history-now-digitized-and-online/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RootsTech 2026 Bonus and Benefits</title>
      <link>https://genealogysstar.blogspot.com/2025/12/rootstech-2026-bonus-and-benefits.html</link>
      <description>Genealogy&amp;#8217;s Star: &amp;#8220;RootsTech 2026, the largest genealogy and family history conference in the world, is scheduled for Marth 5-7, 2026 online and in person at the Salt Palace in Salt Lake City, Utah. Meanwhile, by visiting the website, you can enjoy and learn from the following activities and learning opportunities.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://genealogysstar.blogspot.com/2025/12/rootstech-2026-bonus-and-benefits.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to upgrade your &amp;#8216;incompatible&amp;#8217; Windows 10 PC to Windows 11 now &amp;#8211; for free</title>
      <link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/how-to-upgrade-your-incompatible-windows-10-pc-to-windows-11-for-free-today/</link>
      <description>ZDNet: &amp;#8220;Microsoft really doesn&amp;#8217;t want customers to upgrade older PCs to Windows 11, but there are workarounds for all but the oldest devices. Now that Windows 10 support has officially ended, here&amp;#8217;s everything you need to know.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.zdnet.com/article/how-to-upgrade-your-incompatible-windows-10-pc-to-windows-11-for-free-today/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, 1919-1997: Widening the range of our digital archives</title>
      <link>https://www.manchester.ac.uk/about/news/the-international-federation-of-red-cross-and-red-crescent-societies-1919-1997-widening-the-range-of-our-digital-archives/</link>
      <description>University of Manchester: &amp;#8220;We are pleased to announce the acquisition of The International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, 1919-1997. This acquisition strengthens the University’s longstanding commitment to furthering the U.N.’s Sustainable Development Goals and also our role as a Northern humanitarianism powerhouse.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.manchester.ac.uk/about/news/the-international-federation-of-red-cross-and-red-crescent-societies-1919-1997-widening-the-range-of-our-digital-archives/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TikTok is blissing out on the dancefloor with Jon Hamm</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/jon-hamm-tiktok-meme</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;If you&amp;#8217;ve noticed Jon Hamm perpetually blissing out on a blue-hued dancefloor on your FYP, join the club. The latest TikTok meme is seeing quietly victorious creators stitching a scene featuring the actor&amp;#8217;s performance in Apple TV series Your Friends and Neighbors, a series released back in April this year.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/jon-hamm-tiktok-meme</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disney Hits Google With AI Copyright Infringement Cease-and-Desist Letter</title>
      <link>https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/disney-google-cease-and-desist-letter-1236448009/</link>
      <description>Hollywood Reporter: &amp;#8220;Disney has sent a cease-and-desist letter to Google accusing the tech giant of using Disney’s copyrighted works to train its AI models.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/disney-google-cease-and-desist-letter-1236448009/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Bluebird wants to relaunch “Twitter,” says Musk abandoned the name and logo</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/can-twitter-fly-again-startup-wants-to-pry-iconic-trademark-from-musks-x/</link>
      <description>Ars Technica: &amp;#8220;A Virginia startup calling itself &amp;#8216;Operation Bluebird&amp;#8217; announced this week that it has filed a formal petition with the US Patent and Trademark Office, asking the federal agency to cancel X Corporation’s trademarks of the words &amp;#8216;Twitter&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;tweet&amp;#8217; since X has allegedly abandoned them.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/can-twitter-fly-again-startup-wants-to-pry-iconic-trademark-from-musks-x/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owner of Robux gambling site must face unfair competition claims by underage users</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/owner-of-robux-gambling-site-must-face-unfair-competition-claims-by-underage-users/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;The owner of a now-defunct online casino that targeted Roblox users failed to convince a federal judge to toss the claims brought against him in a proposed class action on behalf of children who gambled away their virtual Robux on his and other websites.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/owner-of-robux-gambling-site-must-face-unfair-competition-claims-by-underage-users/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the future of libraries through arts and technology research</title>
      <link>https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/news/exploring-the-future-of-libraries-through-arts-and-technology-research</link>
      <description>Lancaster University: &amp;#8220;The new book by Dr Nathan Jones, from Lancaster University’s School of Arts, and Dr Sam Skinner (Oxford Brookes University) rethinks what a library might be in the future. Across essays, artworks, and conversations, BiblioTech traces how the next phase in the life of the library will reflect every aspect of contemporary life — from mental health and automation to social justice and climate change.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/news/exploring-the-future-of-libraries-through-arts-and-technology-research</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. I think I need to order more boxes. I&amp;#8217;m playing box-chicken with the stuff I have left to pack. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAHR Announces its New Database “Truth and Reconciliation Mechanisms Archives Locator” (TRMAL) on International Human Rights Day and Discusses Human Rights Archives</title>
      <link>https://www.ica.org/sahr-announces-its-new-database/</link>
      <description>International Council on Archives: &amp;#8220;The TRMAL is a unique tool that for the first time allows researchers, conflict-affected citizens, legal scholars and anyone interested to search for the archives that have been created through a diverse range of mechanisms after conflict. Since 1951, hundreds of commissions have investigated and collected evidence or testimonies related to past human rights violations all over the world. Called Truth and Reconciliation Commission, Investigative Commission or Commission of Inquiry, these missions have been conducted at local, national or international level.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ica.org/sahr-announces-its-new-database/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 in Review</title>
      <link>https://2025inreview.tumblr.com/</link>
      <description>Tumblr: &amp;#8220;This year, we took a closer look at the culture bubbling up through tag data and across your dashboards in 2025—the communities, aesthetics, and micro-moments that shaped the year and show no signs of stopping. (Don&amp;#8217;t worry—if you’re all about that ships list, keep an eye out for it in the New Year  We’ve broken it down into five chapters, each one illustrated by the posts that best capture the moment, because Tumblr is the people here (including you!), and the posts they make along the way.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025inreview.tumblr.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Photos rolls out new video editing tools</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/google-photos-rolls-out-new-video-editing-tools</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;Google is rolling out a suite of new video editing tools for Google Photos, making it easier for users to craft polished highlight reels directly from their phones. The updates, announced in a press release, expand on the app’s existing highlight video feature and introduce more creative control for Android and iOS users.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/google-photos-rolls-out-new-video-editing-tools</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Hacks Every Chromebook Power User Should Know</title>
      <link>https://lifehacker.com/tech/best-hacks-for-chromebook-power-users?utm_medium=RSS</link>
      <description>Lifehacker: &amp;#8220;These hacks are for power users who want to level up their Chromebook capabilities, and get extra value out of their laptop, beyond the standard use cases that everyone knows about. No matter how you use ChromeOS, there should be something here to help.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lifehacker.com/tech/best-hacks-for-chromebook-power-users?utm_medium=RSS</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why RSS matters</title>
      <link>https://werd.io/why-rss-matters/</link>
      <description>Ben Werdmuller: &amp;#8220;When people think about RSS, they most often associate it with the long-departed Google Reader — but it’s far from dead. From direct subscriptions to syndication into apps that aggregate and re-present content, RSS remains the standard for feeds. It’s the glue that holds the timely web together.&amp;#8221; Lots of tools available at RSSGizmos.com!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://werd.io/why-rss-matters/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 230 environmental groups across the US are asking Congress to halt AI data-center expansion</title>
      <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/110529-hundreds-environmental-organizations-asking-congress-halt-new-data.html</link>
      <description>TechSpot: &amp;#8220;A large coalition of environmentally-focused organizations has sent a scathing letter to members of Congress, urging US representatives to put the development of new data centers on hold. The letter identifies generative AI and cryptocurrency as among the most significant environmental and social threats of this generation, citing their role in fueling an unregulated expansion of data centers across the country.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techspot.com/news/110529-hundreds-environmental-organizations-asking-congress-halt-new-data.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google faces $129 million French asset freeze after Russian ruling, documents show</title>
      <link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/google-faces-129-million-french-172033648.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;The administrator of Google&amp;#8217;s (GOOG) defunct Russian business has obtained a temporary freeze on some 110 million euros ($129 ​million) of the Alphabet-owned company&amp;#8217;s assets in France, official orders seen by Reuters show.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/google-faces-129-million-french-172033648.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump sued by preservationists seeking reviews and congressional approval for ballroom project</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/trump-white-house-ballroom-sued-preservationists-76dc3bbea28257e79f8becd487d2c4d7</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;The National Trust for Historic Preservation, a privately funded group, is asking the U.S. District Court to block Trump’s White House ballroom addition, which already has involved razing the East Wing, until it goes through comprehensive design reviews, environmental assessments, public comments and congressional debate and ratification.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/trump-white-house-ballroom-sued-preservationists-76dc3bbea28257e79f8becd487d2c4d7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hundreds of British Empire artifacts stolen from U.K. museum, as police release images of men carrying bags</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/british-empire-artifacts-stolen-uk-museum-police/</link>
      <description>CBS News: &amp;#8220;More than 600 items from a collection documenting the links between Britain and countries in the former British Empire were stolen from a U.K. museum in September, police said Thursday.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/british-empire-artifacts-stolen-uk-museum-police/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>65% of AI chats have no commercial intent, new analysis finds</title>
      <link>https://searchengineland.com/ai-chats-no-commercial-intent-analysis-465928</link>
      <description>Search Engine Land: &amp;#8220;Most AI chats have no commercial intent, users usually ask short questions, and most conversations end after just two turns. Those findings come from a recent analysis by Dan Petrovic, director of AI SEO agency Dejan, who examined millions of conversational turns to show how people actually use AI assistants.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://searchengineland.com/ai-chats-no-commercial-intent-analysis-465928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problem with the school smartphone debate</title>
      <link>https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2025/12/the-problem-with-school-smartphone-debate/</link>
      <description>Harvard Gazette: &amp;#8220;Amid concern about student screen time and mental health, new research indicates that most U.S. public schools already have policies regulating the use of smartphones in class. Hao Yu, associate professor of population medicine at Harvard Medical School and at the Harvard Pilgrim Health Care Institute, said his finding raises the question of whether the policies are being enforced.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2025/12/the-problem-with-school-smartphone-debate/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Videos of sexually suggestive, AI-generated children are racking up millions of likes on TikTok, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/12/11/tech/tiktok-ai-videos-children-report?cid=external-feeds_iluminar_flipboard</link>
      <description>CNN: &amp;#8220;Researchers found more than a dozen accounts posting videos featuring AI-generated girls wearing tight clothing, lingerie or school uniforms, sometimes in suggestive positions. The accounts have hundreds of thousands of followers combined. Comments on many of the videos included links to chats on the messaging platform Telegram, which offered child pornography for purchase, according to the report.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.cnn.com/2025/12/11/tech/tiktok-ai-videos-children-report?cid=external-feeds_iluminar_flipboard</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Spending the day packing. The DUST! Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New WMO Database on National Laws and Decrees Regulating Meteorology &amp;#038; Hydrology</title>
      <link>https://wmo.int/media/announcement/new-wmo-database-national-laws-and-decrees-regulating-meteorology-hydrology</link>
      <description>World Meteorological Organization: &amp;#8220;The World Meteorological Organization (WMO) is pleased to announce the launch of a new database that compiles national laws and decrees governing meteorology and hydrology across all WMO Members. This resource provides a clear, accessible overview of the legal frameworks that define and reinforce the role of National Meteorological and Hydrological Services (NMHSs).&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wmo.int/media/announcement/new-wmo-database-national-laws-and-decrees-regulating-meteorology-hydrology</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brewery and distillery search engine launches</title>
      <link>https://www.thedrinksbusiness.com/2025/12/brewery-and-distillery-search-engine-launches/</link>
      <description>The Drinks Business: &amp;#8220;A new internet search engine, dedicated to helping put beer and whisky drinkers in touch with some of the best breweries and distilleries in Scotland, will debut this week.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedrinksbusiness.com/2025/12/brewery-and-distillery-search-engine-launches/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Update expands archive of vanished Microsoft downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/legacy_update_update/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;Legacy Update has for years been a tremendously useful site and tool for those wanting to keep older versions of Windows alive and in active use. The site has updated its archive of files that Microsoft used to make available for free download in the official Download Center, but has in its finite wisdom removed.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/legacy_update_update/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A.I. Videos Have Flooded Social Media. No One Was Ready.</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/08/technology/ai-slop-sora-social-media.html?unlocked_article_code=1.7k8.IOqX.HIPfdShpqIYd&amp;#038;smid=url-share</link>
      <description>New York Times: This link goes to a gift article. &amp;#8220;In the two months since Sora arrived, deceptive videos have surged on TikTok, X, YouTube, Facebook and Instagram, according to experts who track them&amp;#8230;. Most of the major social media companies have policies that require disclosure of artificial intelligence use and broadly prohibit content intended to deceive. But those guardrails have proved woefully inadequate for the kind of technological leaps OpenAI’s tools represent.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/08/technology/ai-slop-sora-social-media.html?unlocked_article_code=1.7k8.IOqX.HIPfdShpqIYd&amp;#038;smid=url-share</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vermont rescue team sees increase of calls as social media lures skiers into danger</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/skiing-stowe-social-media-rescue-backcountry-39fa381ae3ba9194f9a9a823dcfb02f9?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=693871e5533ab800019b9464&amp;#038;utm_campaign=TrueAnthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=AP&amp;#038;utm_source=Bluesky</link>
      <description>Associated Press: &amp;#8220;A rescue team that covers Vermont’s tallest mountain has seen a rise in calls from inexperienced skiers who end up getting lost and in dangerous locations after being influenced by videos on social media.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://apnews.com/article/skiing-stowe-social-media-rescue-backcountry-39fa381ae3ba9194f9a9a823dcfb02f9?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;#038;taid=693871e5533ab800019b9464&amp;#038;utm_campaign=TrueAnthem&amp;#038;utm_medium=AP&amp;#038;utm_source=Bluesky</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This website literally walks you through the coolest parts of the internet</title>
      <link>https://www.makeuseof.com/this-website-literally-walks-you-through-coolest-parts-of-internet/</link>
      <description>MakeUseOf: &amp;#8220;I once discovered a website that allows me to listen to radio stations from around the world for free. But this time, I might have found one that’s even better: Viralwalk, a website that allows me to discover some of the coolest sites on the web. I’d give fair warning: don’t visit this website if you don&amp;#8217;t want to waste a few hours.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.makeuseof.com/this-website-literally-walks-you-through-coolest-parts-of-internet/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Petco reveals a hack exposed customer data in these states</title>
      <link>https://mashable.com/article/petco-breach-customer-data</link>
      <description>Mashable: &amp;#8220;Petco has confirmed that its data security breach exposed sensitive customer information.  The company initially acknowledged a breach without detailing what was compromised, legal notices that were required in several states are starting to show the scope of the hack.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mashable.com/article/petco-breach-customer-data</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian AI royalty proposal targets data practices of OpenAI, Google</title>
      <link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/indian-ai-royalty-proposal-targets-100007483.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;An Indian government panel has proposed requiring AI companies to pay content creators a share of revenue ​for using their work to train models, a setback for companies such as ‌OpenAI and Google that back free access to publicly available data.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/indian-ai-royalty-proposal-targets-100007483.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calif. woman sentenced after bragging about luxury lifestyle on Instagram</title>
      <link>https://www.sfgate.com/bayarea/article/california-usps-worker-stolen-cards-instagram-21233059.php</link>
      <description>SF Gate: &amp;#8220;Mary Ann Magdamit, a 31-year-old former mail carrier with the United States Postal Service, worked at the Torrance Main Post Office, where she stole checks and sensitive personal information from at least 2022 until July 2025. &amp;#8230; Under the Instagram handle @yourfawkenmom, Magdamit posted photos flaunting $100 bills, luxury goods and her international travels.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sfgate.com/bayarea/article/california-usps-worker-stolen-cards-instagram-21233059.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly one-third of teens use AI chatbots daily</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/ai/nearly-one-third-of-teens-use-ai-chatbots-daily-200000888.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;AI chatbots haven&amp;#8217;t come close to replacing teens&amp;#8217; social media habits, but they are playing a significant role in their online habits. Nearly one-third of US teens report using AI chatbots daily or more, according to a new report from Pew Research.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/ai/nearly-one-third-of-teens-use-ai-chatbots-daily-200000888.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Spending the day packing. The DUST! Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belarus: Where Independent Work is Branded Extremism</title>
      <link>https://publishingperspectives.com/2025/12/belarus-where-independent-work-is-branded-extremism/</link>
      <description>Publishing Perspectives: &amp;#8220;On November 27, PEN Belarus and the Belarusian Association of Journalists hosted an event&amp;#8230;where authors and journalists shared powerful testimonies about life and publishing under the authoritarian regime and introduced a new website dedicated to banned books in Belarus in order to give a platform to the writers who are being silenced.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://publishingperspectives.com/2025/12/belarus-where-independent-work-is-branded-extremism/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Jewish Museum Berlin and Freie Universität Berlin Present Claude Lanzmann’s Audio Archive</title>
      <link>https://www.fu-berlin.de/en/presse/informationen/fup/2025/fup_25_197-claude-lanzmann-ausstellung-ohd-interviewsammlungen/index.html</link>
      <description>Free University Berlin: &amp;#8220;To mark one hundred years since the birth of Claude Lanzmann (1925–2018), the acclaimed French journalist, filmmaker, and chronicler of the Shoah, the Jewish Museum Berlin will be making Lanzmann’s audio archive accessible to the public for the first time. These recordings, made primarily during the 1970s, will be made available on Freie Universität Berlin’s Oral-History.Digital platform.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.fu-berlin.de/en/presse/informationen/fup/2025/fup_25_197-claude-lanzmann-ausstellung-ohd-interviewsammlungen/index.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready To Enter A New Decade With The Next Public Domain Game Jam: Gaming Like It’s 1930!</title>
      <link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/12/09/get-ready-to-enter-a-new-decade-with-the-next-public-domain-game-jam-gaming-like-its-1930/</link>
      <description>Techdirt: &amp;#8220;The new year is approaching fast, and you know what that means: new material is entering the public domain in the US, and we’ll be celebrating it with the eighth installment of our public domain game jam. What’s more, this is an extra special year because the ever-growing public domain is hitting a new decade: it’s time for Gaming Like It’s 1930!&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/12/09/get-ready-to-enter-a-new-decade-with-the-next-public-domain-game-jam-gaming-like-its-1930/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google confirms it releases smaller, unannounced core updates</title>
      <link>https://searchengineland.com/google-confirms-it-releases-smaller-core-updates-it-does-not-announce-465947</link>
      <description>Search Engine Land: &amp;#8220;Plus, a major Google core update is coming soon, which could bring significant ranking changes as it rolls out. Google added a new section to its core updates search developer documentation confirming it sometimes rolls out smaller, unannounced core updates. Google said this before, but now it’s stated explicitly in the official search documentation.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://searchengineland.com/google-confirms-it-releases-smaller-core-updates-it-does-not-announce-465947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix is leaning on YouTube to defend its Warner Bros. acquisition</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/09/netflix-is-leaning-on-youtube-to-defend-its-warner-bros-acquisition/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;YouTube has quite suddenly become a key player in Netflix‘s plans to acquire Warner Bros. Discovery. The streamer announced last week that it would get a Hollywood level-up by purchasing Warner Bros. Discovery’s studio and streaming assets in a deal valued at $82.7 billion (aka $27.75 per share). That deal came after a tense bidding war–and one of the losers isn’t going down without a fight.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/09/netflix-is-leaning-on-youtube-to-defend-its-warner-bros-acquisition/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drury University student creates database to connect Missouri playwrights with schools</title>
      <link>https://www.ky3.com/2025/12/08/drury-university-student-creates-database-connect-missouri-playwrights-with-schools/</link>
      <description>KY3: &amp;#8220;A Drury University student is developing the first database designed to connect local playwrights directly with Missouri schools, potentially making theatre more accessible across the state. Katie Mizell, a senior theatre administration major from Lebanon, created the Missouri Playwrights Educational Database to address barriers facing small theatre programs.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ky3.com/2025/12/08/drury-university-student-creates-database-connect-missouri-playwrights-with-schools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An AI copycat of King Gizzard &amp;#038; the Lizard Wizard went unnoticed on Spotify for weeks</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/streaming/an-ai-copycat-of-king-gizzard--the-lizard-wizard-went-unnoticed-on-spotify-for-weeks-220018144.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;Despite making some moves to address the proliferation of AI-generated audio on its platform, Spotify failed to catch a copycat making imitations of music by King Gizzard &amp;#038; the Lizard Wizard. The long-running experimental rock band from Australia, has been a vocal critic of Spotify and was one of several artists that took their music off the platform in the summer.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/entertainment/streaming/an-ai-copycat-of-king-gizzard--the-lizard-wizard-went-unnoticed-on-spotify-for-weeks-220018144.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI sued for allegedly enabling murder-suicide</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2025/12/11/openai-sued-for-allegedly-enabling-murder-suicide</link>
      <description>Al Jazeera: &amp;#8220;The lawsuit, filed on Thursday, said that ChatGPT fuelled 56-year-old Stein-Erik Soelberg’s delusions of a vast conspiracy against him, and eventually led him to murder his 83-year-old mother, Suzanne Adams, in Connecticut in August.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2025/12/11/openai-sued-for-allegedly-enabling-murder-suicide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>App That Tracks ICE Raids Sues U.S., Saying Officials Pressured Apple to Remove It</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/08/business/apple-iceblock-lawsuit.html?unlocked_article_code=1.7U8.XWf7.tfg0ja5b9Ahe&amp;#038;smid=url-share</link>
      <description>New York Times: This link goes to a gift article. &amp;#8220;For six months, Apple distributed an app called ICEBlock that allowed users to alert people when they saw Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents. But after the Trump administration complained that the app endangered officers, Apple removed it. On Monday, the app developer, Joshua Aaron, sued top Trump administration officials, accusing them of pressuring Apple to stifle his free speech and his right to create, distribute and promote ICEBlock.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/08/business/apple-iceblock-lawsuit.html?unlocked_article_code=1.7U8.XWf7.tfg0ja5b9Ahe&amp;#038;smid=url-share</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New industry standard calls for better record-keeping to protect Indigenous data</title>
      <link>https://ictnews.org/uncategorized/new-industry-standard-calls-for-better-record-keeping-to-protect-indigenous-data/</link>
      <description>IndiJ Public Media: &amp;#8220;A new standard developed in partnership with Indigenous data sovereignty experts at the University of Arizona, New York University, Harvard University and multiple international universities outlines how scientists and technology professionals should record the origin and history of use for data about and relating to Indigenous people.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ictnews.org/uncategorized/new-industry-standard-calls-for-better-record-keeping-to-protect-indigenous-data/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s working, not on front lines of AI in classroom</title>
      <link>https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2025/12/whats-working-not-on-front-lines-of-ai-in-classroom/</link>
      <description>Harvard Gazette: &amp;#8220;To share the innovative ways in which they’re bringing AI into the classroom, Harvard’s Graduate School of Education brought together an education researcher, a tech entrepreneur, and a school superintendent to discuss what’s working, what’s not, and what we still don’t know about utilizing AI’s capabilities.&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2025/12/whats-working-not-on-front-lines-of-ai-in-classroom/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Do y&amp;#8217;all ever wonder when I make these newsletters? Currently it is 5:17 am. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Google Maps quietly allocates survival across London’s restaurants &amp;#8211; and how I built a dashboard to see through it</title>
      <link>https://laurenleek.substack.com/p/how-google-maps-quietly-allocates</link>
      <description>Lauren Leek: &amp;#8220;I built the London food dashboard. The dashboard currently allows users to search by name and filter by underrated gems (identified by my machine learning algorithm), cuisine, borough, price level, min rating, and review volume. It is still very much a version-one prototype &amp;#8211; but it is already a working microscope into London’s algorithmic food economy.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://laurenleek.substack.com/p/how-google-maps-quietly-allocates</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta offers EU users ad-light option in push to end investigation</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/meta-offers-eu-users-ad-light-option-in-push-to-end-investigation/</link>
      <description>Ars Technica: &amp;#8220;Meta has agreed to make changes to its &amp;#8216;pay or consent&amp;#8217; business model in the EU, seeking to agree to a deal that avoids further regulatory fines at a time when the bloc’s digital rule book is drawing anger from US authorities.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/meta-offers-eu-users-ad-light-option-in-push-to-end-investigation/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&amp;#8217;t sell your old mini PC—do these 8 things instead</title>
      <link>https://www.howtogeek.com/ways-to-repurpose-an-old-mini-pc/</link>
      <description>How-To Geek: &amp;#8220;Have an old mini PC lying around you&amp;#8217;re mulling over chucking into your &amp;#8220;hardware graveyard&amp;#8221; drawer or selling on eBay or Facebook Marketplace? Why get rid of it when you can repurpose and breathe new life into it? Here are some roles most mini PCs should excel at.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.howtogeek.com/ways-to-repurpose-an-old-mini-pc/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out Of This World: Little Dot Studios Behind First YouTube Original Doc Made Purely From Getty Images’ Archive</title>
      <link>https://deadline.com/2025/12/little-dot-studios-getty-images-moons-of-our-solar-system-1236644568/</link>
      <description>Deadline: &amp;#8220;Getty Images and Little Dot Studios are teaming to make a two-part, 90-minute science documentaries that will launch on YouTube. Notably, Moons of Our Solar System will be the first made exclusively from Getty Images’ giant online image and video archive.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deadline.com/2025/12/little-dot-studios-getty-images-moons-of-our-solar-system-1236644568/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artist’s Collection of Weird Google Street View Images Gets Major Exhibit</title>
      <link>https://petapixel.com/2025/12/10/artists-collection-of-weird-google-street-view-images-gets-major-exhibit/</link>
      <description>PetaPixel: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230; artist Jon Rafman has been collecting moments captured by Google’s Street View cars&amp;#8230;. The exhibition at the Louisiana is called Report a Concern, a nod to the message Google used to place in the corner of all its images.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://petapixel.com/2025/12/10/artists-collection-of-weird-google-street-view-images-gets-major-exhibit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Google workers one step closer to $50 million settlement in discrimination lawsuit</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/black-google-workers-one-step-closer-to-50-million-settlement-in-discrimination-lawsuit/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;[April] Curley and thousands of other Black Google employees are a step closer to compensation they say the company owes them for what they describe as years of systemic racial discrimination. On Sunday, U.S. Magistrate Judge Kandis Westmore in the Northern District of California granted preliminary approval of a $50 million class action settlement in the case.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/black-google-workers-one-step-closer-to-50-million-settlement-in-discrimination-lawsuit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress removes right to repair language from 2026 defense bill</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/congress-removes-right-to-repair-language-from-2026-defense-bill-231708835.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>Engadget: &amp;#8220;According to a statement from the Public Interest Research Group, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026 has removed language that would have granted the US military the right to repair its own equipment rather than requiring it to use official defense contractors for maintenance.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/congress-removes-right-to-repair-language-from-2026-defense-bill-231708835.html?src=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly Expanding Local News Networks</title>
      <link>https://localnewsinitiative.northwestern.edu/posts/2025/12/02/local-networks-expanding-tapinto-texas-tribune-salt-lake-tribune/index.html</link>
      <description>Local News Initiative: &amp;#8220;In Medill’s 2025 State of Local News Report, one of the fastest growing categories of new local news organizations was outlets that are part of national networks, like TAPinto. There are now 853 local news sites across 52 networks providing original reporting, according to the report.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://localnewsinitiative.northwestern.edu/posts/2025/12/02/local-networks-expanding-tapinto-texas-tribune-salt-lake-tribune/index.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People spending even more time online now than during the pandemic</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c39prelx2mxo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</link>
      <description>BBC: &amp;#8220;UK adults spent over half an hour longer online every day in 2025 than they did during the pandemic, according to an annual survey of internet habits by the regulator Ofcom. The Online Nation report found on average, people in the UK spent four hours and 30 minutes online every day in 2025 &amp;#8211; 31 minutes longer than in 2021.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c39prelx2mxo?at_medium=RSS&amp;#038;at_campaign=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>See the Skies at Their Most Magical With the Best Aurora Photos of 2025</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/see-the-skies-at-their-most-magical-with-the-best-aurora-photos-of-2025-2000696877</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;[Tori] Harp’s photograph is one of 25 winners of the 2025 Northern Lights Photographer of the Year competition, hosted by travel blog Capture the Atlas to honor images that illustrate the surreal beauty of the Northern Lights. And what a year it’s been, with the Sun, now in its solar maximum phase, unleashing geomagnetic storms that lit up the skies with dazzling displays.&amp;#8221; Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/see-the-skies-at-their-most-magical-with-the-best-aurora-photos-of-2025-2000696877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. Do y&amp;#8217;all ever wonder when I make these newsletters? Currently it is 5:17 am. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free online resource shows people how to identify poisonous Virginia mushrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.dnronline.com/news/health/free-online-resource-shows-people-how-to-identify-poisonous-virginia-mushrooms/article_6d749508-f0a8-57bd-8192-177d643fa665.html</link>
      <description>Daily News-Record: &amp;#8220;The book covers the top 40 of the state’s more than 2,700 poisonous mushrooms, [Dave] Saylor said. Within the 125-page book, each mushroom is described, and color photos are included. Then, information is provided on where the mushroom can be found, what makes it poisonous, the symptoms of poisoning by a particular mushroom, which non-poisonous mushrooms it may be mistaken for, and notes on each mushroom.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dnronline.com/news/health/free-online-resource-shows-people-how-to-identify-poisonous-virginia-mushrooms/article_6d749508-f0a8-57bd-8192-177d643fa665.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Disputes Report Claiming Ads Are Coming To Gemini In 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.searchenginejournal.com/google-disputes-report-claiming-ads-are-coming-to-gemini-in-2026/562831/</link>
      <description>Search Engine Journal: &amp;#8220;Google is publicly pushing back on an Adweek report that claimed the company told advertising clients it plans to bring ads to its Gemini AI chatbot next year. Dan Taylor, Google’s Vice President of Global Ads, responded directly on X shortly after the story published, calling the report inaccurate and denying any plans to monetize the Gemini app.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.searchenginejournal.com/google-disputes-report-claiming-ads-are-coming-to-gemini-in-2026/562831/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube TV to launch genre-based subscription plans in 2026</title>
      <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/10/youtube-tv-to-launch-genre-based-subscription-plans-in-2026/</link>
      <description>TechCrunch: &amp;#8220;YouTube TV is launching more than 10 genre-specific channel packages in early 2026, the Google-owned company announced on Wednesday. The move will mark the first time YouTube TV breaks up its cable-like channel bundle.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/10/youtube-tv-to-launch-genre-based-subscription-plans-in-2026/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Age verification errors see some under-16s retain access to banned social media platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-media-ban-day-one-teen-access/106126706</link>
      <description>ABC News (Australia): &amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s day one of the social media ban and, unsurprisingly, it hasn&amp;#8217;t been a smooth launch. Many children have already been able to get around the ban in various ways, with age assurance systems misclassifying users and workarounds such as VPNs and make-up tricks being used.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-media-ban-day-one-teen-access/106126706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These YouTube add-ons make watching long videos actually enjoyable</title>
      <link>https://www.makeuseof.com/youtube-add-ons-make-watching-long-videos-actually-enjoyable/</link>
      <description>MakeUseOf: &amp;#8220;The good news is that you are not stuck with YouTube in its default, chaotic form. With a carefully chosen set of browser extensions, you can peel away the noise and restore YouTube to what it was supposed to be: a focused space for entertainment and learning.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.makeuseof.com/youtube-add-ons-make-watching-long-videos-actually-enjoyable/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign states using AI videos to undermine support for Ukraine, says Yvette Cooper</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/dec/08/foreign-states-ai-videos-support-ukraine-yvette-cooper</link>
      <description>The Guardian: &amp;#8220;Foreign countries are flooding social media with AI-manipulated videos to undermine western support for Ukraine, Yvette Cooper will warn on Tuesday. The UK foreign secretary will urge other countries to help Britain fight what she calls &amp;#8216;information warfare&amp;#8217;, as officials warn Russia is using forged documents and deepfake material to advance its geopolitical goals.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/dec/08/foreign-states-ai-videos-support-ukraine-yvette-cooper</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Universities Help Students Become Influencers?</title>
      <link>https://www.insidehighered.com/news/students/careers/2025/12/08/syracuse-other-universities-launch-content-creation-programs</link>
      <description>Inside Higher Ed: &amp;#8220;The center, which will officially launch this spring, will develop upward of 12 courses related to content creation, from technical skills to how to build a brand; by fall 2026, the center will offer a full-fledged content creation minor. It will also be home to a content creation makerspace, currently under construction, where Syracuse students can utilize high-quality cameras, green screens, podcasting booths and more.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.insidehighered.com/news/students/careers/2025/12/08/syracuse-other-universities-launch-content-creation-programs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive-Google faces fines over Google Play if it doesn&amp;#8217;t make more concessions, sources say</title>
      <link>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/exclusive-google-faces-fines-over-165514065.html</link>
      <description>Reuters: &amp;#8220;Alphabet&amp;#8217;s Google is set to be hit with a potentially large EU fine early next year if it does not do more to ​ensure that its app store complies with EU rules aimed at ensuring fair access and competition, ‌people with direct knowledge of the matter said.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/exclusive-google-faces-fines-over-165514065.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 70 Domains Used in Months-Long Phishing Spree Against US Universities</title>
      <link>https://hackread.com/us-universities-domains-phishing-attacks/</link>
      <description>Hackread: &amp;#8220;Anew report from security firm Infoblox reveals that at least 18 American universities have been hit by a prolonged, coordinated phishing attack over a period of many months.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackread.com/us-universities-domains-phishing-attacks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TikTok may be big in Asia, but its U.S. user base is a goldmine</title>
      <link>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/08/tiktok-us-ecommerce-consumer-value-emarketer/</link>
      <description>Tubefilter: &amp;#8220;As the 2025 holiday season hits its stride, eMarketer is explaining just how much American users impact TikTok‘s bottom line. The data firm published a report in which it claims that U.S. users generate 41% of TikTok’s ad revenue, even though they only account for 10% of the app’s overall user count.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.tubefilter.com/2025/12/08/tiktok-us-ecommerce-consumer-value-emarketer/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishers say no to AI scrapers, block bots at server level</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/08/publishers_say_no_ai_scrapers/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;Online traffic analysis conducted by BuiltWith, a web metrics biz, indicates that the number of publishers trying to prevent AI bots from scraping content for use in model training has surged since July. About 5.6 million websites presently have added OpenAI&amp;#8217;s GPTBot to the disallow list in their robots.txt file, up from about 3.3 million at the start of July 2025. That&amp;#8217;s an increase of almost 70 percent.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/08/publishers_say_no_ai_scrapers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hawai‘i CC expands traditional Hawaiian place name mapping</title>
      <link>https://www.hawaii.edu/news/2025/12/08/hawaii-cc-traditional-mapping/</link>
      <description>University of Hawaii: &amp;#8220;Hawaiʻi Community College faculty, staff and students are helping revive the traditional place names of Hawaiʻi Island through a growing series of bilingual geographic maps that honor ancestral knowledge and strengthen community connection to the ʻāina (land).&amp;#8221; Good morning, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hawaii.edu/news/2025/12/08/hawaii-cc-traditional-mapping/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. The shredder man came this morning! My 1992 tax return is finally confetti. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UEA&amp;#8217;s Institute for Volunteering Research releases archive</title>
      <link>https://www.edp24.co.uk/news/25676818.ueas-institute-volunteering-research-releases-archive/</link>
      <description>Eastern Daily Press: &amp;#8220;A new archive showcasing 25 years of volunteering research has been launched by the University of East Anglia. Published by the university’s Institute for Volunteering Research (IVR), the archive is now publicly available online for the first time and includes decades of studies, resources and toolkits.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.edp24.co.uk/news/25676818.ueas-institute-volunteering-research-releases-archive/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McDonald&amp;#8217;s pulls AI Christmas ad after backlash</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czdgrnvp082o</link>
      <description>BBC: &amp;#8220;McDonald&amp;#8217;s has taken down a Christmas advert made with Artificial Intelligence (AI) following online backlash. The 45-second advert was produced with generative AI clips and released publicly on McDonald&amp;#8217;s Netherlands YouTube channel on 6 December.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czdgrnvp082o</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft reports 7.8-rated zero day, plus 56 more in December Patch Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/09/december_2025_patch_tuesday/</link>
      <description>The Register: &amp;#8220;Happy December Patch Tuesday to all who celebrate. This month&amp;#8217;s patch party includes one Microsoft flaw under exploitation, plus two others listed as publicly known – but just 57 CVEs in total from Redmond. There&amp;#8217;s also a fix for a critical Notepad++ bug that, according to security sleuth Kevin Beaumont, is being abused by attackers in China.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/09/december_2025_patch_tuesday/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to save your old computer? Try one of these 9 Linux distros &amp;#8211; for free</title>
      <link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/want-to-save-your-old-computer-try-one-of-these-9-linux-distros-for-free/</link>
      <description>ZDNet: &amp;#8220;With these operating systems, you can revive an old machine and make it run as though it were new. Here are 9 Linux distributions that are perfectly at home on older (and even newer) hardware.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.zdnet.com/article/want-to-save-your-old-computer-try-one-of-these-9-linux-distros-for-free/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Foundation Announces the Formation of the Agentic AI Foundation (AAIF), Anchored by New Project Contributions Including Model Context Protocol (MCP), goose and AGENTS.md</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press/linux-foundation-announces-the-formation-of-the-agentic-ai-foundation</link>
      <description>The Linux Foundation: &amp;#8220;The Linux Foundation announced the formation of the Agentic AI Foundation (AAIF) with founding contributions of leading technical projects including Anthropic’s Model Context Protocol (MCP), Block’s goose, and OpenAI’s AGENTS.md.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press/linux-foundation-announces-the-formation-of-the-agentic-ai-foundation</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France returns smuggled dinosaur skeleton to Mongolia</title>
      <link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/world/france-returns-smuggled-dinosaur-skeleton-to-mongolia/ar-AA1RWGyB</link>
      <description>AFP: &amp;#8220;France on Monday handed over a 70-million-year-old dinosaur skeleton to Mongolia, which was looted from the Gobi Desert and seized by French customs, as the Asian country seeks to recover lost relics.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/world/france-returns-smuggled-dinosaur-skeleton-to-mongolia/ar-AA1RWGyB</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CBP Announces Plan to Look at Foreign Tourists’ Social Media Activity Prior to U.S. Entry</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/cbp-announces-plan-to-look-at-foreign-tourists-social-media-activity-prior-to-u-s-entry-2000697654</link>
      <description>Gizmodo: &amp;#8220;On Tuesday at the Federal Register, U.S. Customs and Border Patrol posted a proposed policy tweak: It now plans to dig around in tourists’ social media histories before letting them enter, even if they’re coming from some of the least scrutinized countries in the world.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gizmodo.com/cbp-announces-plan-to-look-at-foreign-tourists-social-media-activity-prior-to-u-s-entry-2000697654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feds charge Ukrainian woman with aiding Russian state-backed cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://www.courthousenews.com/feds-charge-ukrainian-woman-with-aiding-russian-state-backed-cyberattacks/</link>
      <description>Courthouse News Service: &amp;#8220;The U.S. Justice Department charged a Ukrainian woman with participating in Russian state-backed cyberattacks aimed at multiple targets around the world, including U.S. election infrastructure, drinking water facilities in several states and a meat processing plant in Los Angeles.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.courthousenews.com/feds-charge-ukrainian-woman-with-aiding-russian-state-backed-cyberattacks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Glasses That Detect Smartglasses</title>
      <link>https://hackaday.com/2025/12/09/making-glasses-that-detect-smartglasses/</link>
      <description>Hackaday: &amp;#8220;[NullPxl]’s Ban-Rays concept is a wearable that detects when one is in the presence of camera-bearing smartglasses, such as Meta’s line of Ray-Bans. A project in progress, it’s currently focused on how to reliably perform detection without resorting to using a camera itself. Right now, it plays a well-known audio cue whenever it gets a hit.&amp;#8221;  Good afternoon, Internet&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackaday.com/2025/12/09/making-glasses-that-detect-smartglasses/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supporting ResearchBuzz on Patreon</title>
      <link>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</link>
      <description>This newsletter is free but most of the things that go into making it aren&amp;#8217;t! Help me afford new socks and fancier bean stew by Not interested in commitment? Perhaps you’d buy me an iced tea. Don&amp;#8217;t have any money but still want to support? I know how that feels. Nobody reads my nonsense. The shredder man came this morning! My 1992 tax return is finally confetti. Share this newsletter or tell a friend about it. I live at Calishat. See my other nonsense at SearchTweaks, RSS Gizmos, Local Search America, WikiTwister, and MiniGladys.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.patreon.com/ResearchBuzz</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>